(Yomiuri TV 60th Anniversary)
(TV Yomiuri Ulang Tahun ke 60)
(Marina Bay Sands)
(Marina Bay Sands)
Here we go.
Silakan.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Did I make you wait?
Apa aku membuatmu menunggu?
This is a strange place to meet.
Ini tempat yang aneh untuk bertemu.
Can we talk in Japanese
Apa kita bisa berbicara dengan bahasa Jepang...
so that people around us won't understand?
sehingga orang di sekitar tidak memahaminya?
(Sherilyn Tan (40) Lawyer) You won't be able to do anything strange.
(Sherilyn Tan, 40, Pengacara) Kau tidak bisa melakukan yang gegabah.
We are in public.
Kita ada di tempat umum.
(Leon Lowe (43) Management Consultant) That's too much.
(Leon Lowe, 43, Konsultan Manajemen) Itu berlebihan.
It's like I'm trying to kill you.
Itu seakan-akan aku mencoba untuk membunuhmu.
Isn't it?
Bukankah begitu?
I've thought you and I had a good relationship as friends.
Kupikir kau dan aku adalah teman yang baik.
No more idle chatter.
Tidak perlu basa-basi lagi.
I just want to hear your response to my proposal.
Aku hanya ingin mendengarkan jawabanmu terhadap proposalku.
Yes or NO?
Iya atau tidak?
Before I answer you.
Sebelum aku menjawabnya.
I'll guess what you ordered.
Aku akan menebak apa yang kau pesan.
It's not iced tea, it's champagne.
Itu bukan es teh, itu adalah sampanye.
No, it's wine.
Tidak, itu anggur.
Not red, white.
Bukan warna merah, tapi putih.
Chilled Meursault.
Meursault dingin.
Here is your Meursault.
Ini Meursault Anda.
How did you know that?
Bagaimana kau bisa tahu?
I can read your mind.
Aku bisa membaca pikiranmu.
- Huh? - No thanks.
- Huh? - Tidak terima kasih.
Oh, hey.
Oh, hei.
What?
Apa?
The answer's NO.
Jawabannya adalah tidak.
Thanks for the help.
Terima kasih atas bantuannya.
Hey, are you okay?
Hei, apa kau baik-baik saja?
What?
Apa?
Please be calm.
Harap tenang.
Follow our instructions.
Ikuti instruksi kami.
Hey wait.
Hei tunggu.
What are you doing?
Apa yang sedang kau lakukan?
Preserving the scene of the crime.
Menjaga keutuhan tempat kejadian.
Otherwise this will be trampled over, right?
Jika tidak nanti akan diinjak-injak, bukan?
Sir!
Pak!
Where I called?
Di mana dia?
His already inside.
Dia sudah ada di dalam.
Thanks.
Terima kasih.
Sorry make you wait. Rishi.
Maaf membuatmu menunggu. Rishi.
Inspector Aidan.
Inspektur Aidan.
Thank you for calling me.
Terima kasih sudah menghubungiku.
The incident happened at the shopping mall ahead.
Kejadiannya terjadi di pusat perbelanjaan di depan.
(Mark Aidan (38), Singapore Police)
(Mark Aidan, 38, Polisi Singapura)
This case could be a little tricky.
Kasus ini mungkin sedikit sulit.
The Leon Lowe.
Leon Lowe.
First discovered the body.
Yang menemukan tubuhnya pertama kali.
Oh! Mr. Lowe!
Oh! Tuan Lowe!
You are his favourite student right?
Kau adalah murid favoritnya bukan?
Could you ask him not to Interfere too much?
Apa kau bisa meminta dia untuk tidak terlalu ikut campur?
I can't ask him that.
Aku tidak bisa meminta itu.
I'll go say hello.
Aku akan menyapanya.
Mr. Lowe.
Tuan Lowe.
Rishi It has been awhile.
Rishi sudah lama sekali.
Yes.
Iya.
Let's speak in Japanese.
Ayo berbicara dengan bahasa Jepang.
Yes, sir.
Baik, pak.
Are you working as
Apa kau bekerja sebagai
a civilian reserve police officer now?
seorang perwira polisi sipil sekarang?
You've got ahead in your career.
Kau sudah maju sekali di karirmu.
Rishi Ramanathan (29) Reserve Police Officer
(Rishi Ramanathan, 29, Perwira Polisi Sipil)
As an instructor,
Sebagai seorang instruktur,
You taught me a criminal behavior psychology.
kau telah mengajariku psikologi perilaku kriminal.
I appreciate your help, Mr. Lowe.
Aku menghargai bantuanmu, Tuan Lowe.
Don't call me Mr. Lowe.
Jangan panggil aku Tuan Lowe.
I'm an ordinary person now.
Aku sekarang adalah orang biasa.
Anyway,
Bagaimanapun,
I didn't expect the criminal prepare bombs.
Aku tidak mengira si pelaku telah menyiapkan bom.
The car that blew up.
Mobil yang meledak itu.
It belonged to the victim, Sherilyn Tan-san.
Itu adalah milik korban, Sherilyn Tan-san.
She was an excellent lawyer.
Dia adalah pengacara hebat.
So, must have had some enemies.
Jadi, dia pasti ada memiliki beberapa musuh.
And associated with vulgar herd.
Dan berasosiasi dengan kawanan vulgar.
Inspector there?
Inspektur di sana?
Excuse me make way.
Permisi tolong beri jalan.
What's going on?
Apa yang terjadi?
There's something on the elevator wall.
Ada sesuatu di dinding lift.
What?
Apa?
What is this?
Apa ini?
No.
Tidak.
Please!
Kumohon!
No is NO.
Tidak tetap tidak.
I really need your help.
Aku benar-benar membutuhkan bantuanmu.
What's wrong with you two?
Ada apa dengan kalian berdua?
He wants to use the potion again.
Dia ingin menggunakan ramuan itu lagi.
To get back to his original appearance.
Untuk menjadi ke ukuran aslinya.
Even during a school trip,
Bahkan saat perjalanan sekolah,
We've been through so much!
kita sudah sangat kerepotan!
At that time
Pada saat itu.
We managed to survive it, too.
Kita berhasil bertahan hidup, juga.
So It'll be fine.
Jadi itu tidak apa-apa.
Give me the potion.
Berikan aku ramuannya.
No!
Tidak!
Where the hell do you think you're going?
Memang kau mau pergi ke mana?
Singapore
Singapura.
Professor Agasa, here it is.
Profesor Agasa, ke sini.
(Karate ZHONHAN CUP) He will be in this championship.
(Turnamen Karate Zhonhan) Dia akan ada di kejuaraan ini.
Undefeated in 400 battles.
Tidak terkalahkan dalam 400 pertarungan.
Oh, you mean Makoto Kyogoku?
Oh, maksudmu Makoto Kyogoku?
Sonoko said she'd go see the match.
Sonoko mengatakan dia akan pergi melihat pertandingannya.
She invited Mister, Kogoro and Ran.
Dia mengundang Paman Kogoro and Ran.
I was also invited, but
Aku juga diundang, tapi...
I can't leave Japan looking like this.
Aku tidak bisa keluar dari Jepang dengan keadaan seperti ini.
I agree.
Aku setuju.
The passport's Shinichi's.
Paspornya milik Shinichi.
So please, Haibara.
Jadi kumohon, Haibara.
You're so persistent.
Kau keras kepala sekali.
It 's better to give up this time...
Sebaiknya menyerah saja untuk kali ini...
I wish I could've gone.
Aku berharap aku bisa pergi.
Don't be so disappointed.
Jangan terlalu kecewa.
Alright, let's do Professor Agasa Quiz for a change.
Baiklah, waktunya untuk Kuis Profesor Agasa.
Are we doing this already?
Apa kita akan melakukan itu?
It's the Asian Quiz!
Ini adalah Kuis Asia!
What is the most
Apa acara yang...
popular event in Singapore?
paling populer di Singapura?
1 Singing the national anthem
1. Menyanyikan lagu kebangsaan.
2 Chinese New Year Celebration
2. Perayaan Tahun Baru Imlek.
3 National Flag Raising
3. Pengibaran Bendera Nasional.
4 Marina Bay Fireworks Show
4. Kembang Api Marina bay.
What is that outfit?
Apa-apaan dengan pakaian itu?
The answer is simple.
Jawabannya mudah.
It's number 3, National Flag Raising.
Nomor 3, Pengibaran Bendera Nasional.
After all, it's Singapore!
Lagi pula, itu adalah Singapura!
(The core is flagpole.) Wow! That's correct!
(Intinya adalah tiang bendera.) Wow! Itu benar!
You're the best. Okay, one more quiz.
Kau yang terbaik. Oke, satu kuiz lagi.
That's enough.
Sudah cukup.
I'm missing the kids.
Aku rindu dengan anak-anak.
Damn, Haibara.
Sial, Haibara.
(CAUTION SLOW DOWN)
(Perhatian Turunkan Kecepatan)
Ran!
Ran!
Ran-Neechan, what's wrong?
Ran-Neechan, ada apa?
What are you doing here?
Apa yang kau lakukan di sini?
Ran... -Neechan
Ran... -Neechan
I've been waiting for you.
Aku telah menunggumu.
What is here?
Di mana ini?
- It's huge. - Ran's voice
- Besar sekali. - Itu suara Ran.
Where the hell am I?
Di mana aku sebenarnya?
I've trapped in something.
Aku terjebak di suatu tempat.
Shit.
Sial.
Here we go.
Ini dia.
Merlion?
Merlion?
Singapore.
Singapura.
(Detective Conan, The Fist of Blue Sapphire)
(Detective Conan, Tinju Safir Biru)
I am high school detective Shinichi Kudo.
Aku adalah seorang detektif SMA Shinichi Kudo.
My childhood friend and classmate,  Ran Mouri
Ini adalah teman masa kecilku, Ran Mouri.
We went to an amusement park.
Saat kami pergi ke taman hiburan.
I saw a man in black
Aku menyaksikan adanya transaksi yang...
I witnessed the scene of a dubious dealing situation.
mencurigakan oleh pria berpakaian hitam.
I was concentrating on watching that.
Aku terlalu terpaku menyaksikan transaksi itu.
I didn't notice the other fellow coming up
Dan tidak menyadari rekannya yang menyerang...
behind me.
dari belakangku.
The man gave me a poison.
Orang itu memberiku sebuah racun.
When I woke up,
Dan saat aku terbangun,
My body had shrunk.
tubuhku telah mengecil.
If they find out that  Shinichi Kudo is still alive...
Jika mereka mengetahui Shinichi Kudo masih hidup...
They'll try to kill me again, and harm to everyone around me.
Mereka akan mengincarku lagi, dan bisa membahayakan orang di sekitarku.
I decided to hide my true identity with the advice of Professor Agasa.
Dengan saran dari Profesor Agasa, aku menyembunyikan identitasku.
When Ran asked me my name.
Ketika Ran menanyakan namaku.
I introduced myself, Conan Edogawa on a whim.
Tanpa pikir panjang, aku menyebutkan nama Conan Edogawa.
To get information about them,
Untuk mengumpulkan informasi tentang orang itu,
I crashed at Ran's house,
Aku tinggal bersama Ran,
where his father was a detective.
yang ayahnya merupakan seorang detektif.
And one of my favorite rival is this guy.
Dan orang ini adalah saingan favoritku.
Kaito Kid
Kaito Kid.
He's an unidentified thief and a master of disguise.
Dia adalah pencuri misterius yang ahli menyamar.
Somehow he knows who I am.
Entah bagaimana dia mengetahui identitasku.
I cannot my guard is down to him.
Aku tidak boleh lengah di hadapannya.
Someday I'll catch him myself.
Suatu hari aku akan menangkapnya.
The Kid's favorite rival, Makoto Kyogoku.
Ini adalah saingan favoritnya Kid, Makoto Kyogoku.
He's a high school student.
Dia adalah seorang murid SMA.
And a high school karate master who's undefeated in 400 fights.
Dan seorang ahli karate yang tidak terkalahkan dalam 400 pertarungan.
For some reason, he seems to have a crush on Sonoko Suzuki, a classmate of Ran's.
Untuk suatu alasan, dia sepertinya menyukai Sonoko Suzuki, teman sekelasnya Ran.
The daughter of the Suzuki group.
Putri dari grup Suzuki.
What are you looking at?
Apa yang kau lihat?
Do it as usual one, hurry up.
Lakukan yang seperti biasanya.
Even though I've become smaller, my mind remains the same.
Walau tubuhku mengecil, pikiranku tetap cerdas.
The unbeaten great detective...
Aku adalah detektif yang tidak terkalahkan...
There's always only one truth!
Hanya ada satu kebenaran!
My hands
Tanganku.
And no professor's tools
Dan tidak ada peralatan profesor
I know! Ran's here.
Aku tahu! Ran ada di sini.
Wait, Ran-Neechan.
Tunggu, Ran-Neechan.
Shinichi! Come here!
Shinichi! Kemarilah!
What?
Apa?
I'm sorry.
Maafkan aku.
Sorry to make you wait.
Maaf membuatmu menunggu lama.
Where have you been? I was looking for you.
Kau ke mana saja? Aku sedang mencarimu.
You said it's hot.
Kau tadi mengatakan panas.
So I was leading Mister to the shade.
Jadi aku membawa Paman pergi berteduh.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
He never change, Uncle Kogoro.
Dia tidak pernah berubah, Paman Kogoro.
Hey, Ran...
Hei, Ran...
Can you get me some water?
Apa kau pergi bisa membelikan air?
I can't help it.
Mau bagaimana lagi.
Come with me
Ikut aku.
Come on.
Ayo.
Okay
Baik.
Whoa! It seems so lovey-dovey.
Whoa! Mereka mesra sekali.
You bastard.
Dasar bangsat.
I'm back.
Aku sudah kembali.
Dad, what are you wearing around your neck?
Ayah, apa yang kau kenakan di lehermu?
This is...
Ini adalah...
My passport, I keep it in here.
Pasporku, aku menyimpannya di sini.
I don't want to get lost or stolen it.
Aku tidak ingin kehilangannya.
Nice idea, isn't it?. Hmm?
Ide bagus, bukan? Hmm?
Dad...
Ayah...
You don't have to do this.
Kau tidak harus melakukan ini.
Because Singapore is safe.
Karena Singapura itu aman.
Hey, are you awake?
Hei, kau sudah terbangun?
I knew it, bastard.
Sudah kuduga, bangsat.
Well...
Ya...
How did you get out of that suitcase?
Bagaimana kau bisa keluar dari koper itu?
This is.
Dengan ini.
If I insert the tip of this,
Jika aku menusukkan ini,
it will open unexpectedly easily even from inside.
itu akan membukanya dengan mudah dari dalam.
I thought a ballpoint pen would be no problem.
Aku mengira sebuah bulpen tidak akan menjadi masalah.
I can't be too careful around you.
Aku harus sangat berhati-hati di dekatmu.
That's my line, Kaito Kid.
Itu adalah kalimatku, Kaito Kid.
Oh, there it is.
Oh, di sana dia.
Well, What's the meaning of this?
Ya, apa maksudnya dari ini?
You know exactly what I mean.
Kau pasti tahu apa maksudku.
There it is.
Itu.
(Karate ZOHNHAN CUP)
(Turnamen Karate Zhonhan)
That's Sonoko's
Itu dari Sonoko...
Late 19th century,
Akhir abad ke-19,
A legendary treasure that was said to have sunk
Sebuah harta karun legendaris telah tenggelam...
with a pirate ship in the sea near Singapore
bersamaan dengan kapal bajak laut di dekat laut Singapura.
World's largest blue sapphire
Safir biru terbesar di dunia.
Also known as the Fist of Blue Sapphire.
Yang juga dikenal sebagai "Tinju Safir Biru".
Last year, Mr. Zhon Han Chen successfuly raised
Tahun lalu, Tuan Zhon Han Chen berhasil mengangkat
the big jewel from the sea. That the one.
permata besar itu dari laut. Yang satu itu.
World Watch Salvage Pirates Ship Treasure〜Singapore)
(Berita Dunia, Penyelamatan Harta Karun Bajak Laut, Singapura)
Zhon Han Chen is one of
Zhon Han Chen adalah salah satu...
the most powerful man in Singapore.
orang yang paling penting di Singapura.
(Singapore Tycoon Mr. Zhon Han Chen (70))
(Orang Kaya Singapura ,Mr. Zhon Han Chen, 70)
Yes.
Iya.
And this old man loves martial arts.
Dan pria tua ini menyukai seni bela diri.
He put the jewel in the championship belt.
Dia menempatkan permatanya di sabuk kejuaraan.
He's decided to hold a karate tournament.
Dia memutuskan untuk mengadakan turnamen karate.
The legendary jewel goes to the winner.
Pemenang akan mendapatkan permata yang legendaris.
It's a billionaire's hobby.
Itu adalah hobi seorang milyarder.
Yeah.
Benar.
I was thinking of just taking the jewels
Aku berpikir untuk mengambil permatanya...
in the middle of the tournament.
saat di tengah turnamen.
But as the Kid,
Tapi sebagai Kid,
I can't just enter Singapore.
aku tidak bisa memasuki Singapura.
If all you wanted was the jewels,
Jika kau hanya menginginkan permatanya,
You don't have to bring me here.
kau tidak harus membawaku kemari.
It's a little bit special this time.
Ada yang berbeda kali ini.
I'll tell you about it later.
Aku akan memberitahumu nanti.
Hey!
Hei!
Huh? Shinichi?
Huh? Shinichi?
- He's gone again? - She is looking for me.
- Dia menghilang lagi? - Dia sedang mencariku.
Wait, Kid.
Tunggu, Kid.
If you do anything to Ran,  you're toast!
Jika kau menyentuh Ran, akan kuhajar kau!
Sorry, but I can't guarantee that.
Maaf, tapi aku tidak bisa memastikan itu.
Then I'll tell her who you are right now.
Kalau begitu aku akan membongkar identitasmu sekarang.
You'd better not do that.
Sebaiknya kau tidak melakukan itu.
The only reason you got into Singapore was...
Satu-satunya alasan kau bisa di Singapura...
because of this suitcase.
karena koper ini.
It's a special suitcase that won't pass the X-rays at the baggage check.
Ini adalah koper khusus yang tidak bisa dideteksi X-ray saat pemeriksaan bagasi.
And it is a 12-hour oxygen generator inside.
Dan ini ada generator oksigen 12 jam di dalamnya.
It's filled with the finest cushioning,
Di dalamnya ada bantal yang sangat empuk,
that won't hurt your body even if you're in it for a long flight.
sehingga badanmu tidak akan sakit walau dalam perjalanan yang sangat lama.
Do you understand what this means?
Kau mengerti maksudnya bukan?
Great detective.
Detektif hebat.
Without my help, without your passport,
Tanpa bantuanku, tanpa paspormu,
you can't leave this country.
kau tidak bisa meninggalkan negara ini.
It means you'll never be able to return to Japan.
Yang berarti kau tidak akan bisa kembali ke Jepang.
Shinichi!
Shinichi!
You are always disappear.
Kau selalu menghilang.
Kid.
Bocah.
Why are you here?
Kenapa kau ada di sini?
Conan?
Conan?
Ran away!
Dia melarikan diri!
See, I'm surprised, too.
Lihat, aku juga terkejut.
He's a local kid.
Dia adalah anak dari sini.
Is that so?
Begitukah?
You guys are so easily fooled. - But you look so much alike.
- Kalian benar-benar mudah dikelabui. - Tapi dia mirip sekali.
What's your name?
Siapa namamu?
Do you understand Japanese?
Apa kau mengerti bahasa Jepang?
What?
Apa?
This boy...
Anak ini...
Arthur.
Arthur.
My name is Arthur Hirai.
Namaku Arthur Hirai.
Arthur Hirai?
Arthur Hirai?
My mother is Japanese. And...
Ibuku adalah orang Jepang. Dan...
I'm Sonoko Suzuki.
Namaku Sonoko Suzuki.
I'm Mouri Ran.
Namaku Mouri Ran.
And over there, he is
Dan yang di sana, dia adalah
That's my father, Kogoro Mouri.
ayahku, Kogoro Mouri.
Nice to meet you.
Salam kenal.
Nice to meet you, too.
Salam kenal juga.
I'm sorry, Ran. I have to go.
Maafkan aku, Ran. Aku harus pergi.
Oh...yeah
Oh...iya
Where's your mom and dad?
Di mana ayah dan ibumu?
Um...
Um...
They're in Japan.
Mereka pergi ke Jepang.
Are you home alone, Arthur?
Apa kau tinggal sendirian, Arthur?
Yeah.
Iya.
But don't worry, I'm used to it.
Tapi jangan khawatir, aku sudah terbiasa.
Okay.
Baik.
Then why don't you come with us?
Kalau begitu mau ikut kami?
Are you sure?
Apa kau yakin?
Yeah, sure.
Iya, aku yakin.
I'm gonna go check on my dad.
Aku akan tanya ayahku.
Sure.
Baiklah.
By the way, still not here.
Omong-omong, belum tiba di sini.
He could've texted me at least.
Setidaknya dia bisa mengirimkanku pesan.
It's supposed to meet here.
Seharusnya kami bertemu di sini.
Get out of my way!
Minggir!
What the hell is this?
Apa-apaan ini?
What's with them?
Siapa orang-orang itu?
That's Reijiro Nakatomi in the center.
Itu yang di tengah dalah Reijiro Nakatomi.
Nakatomi? Yes.
Nakatomi? Oh iya.
The president of Nakatomi Shipping.
Presiden dari Pengiriman Nakatomi.
(Reijiro Nakatomi (39))He is a go getter,
(Reijiro Nakatomi, 39) Dia adalah orang yang rajin,
but always giving rise to come scandal or other.
tapi sering membuat skandal atau semacamnya.
Hey, you.
Hei, kau...
All the way to Singapore and all alone?
Kau datang ke Singapura sendirian?
Have a drink with me.
Ayo pergi minum bersamaku.
I don't have time for that right now.
Aku tidak punya waktu untuk itu.
Go away.
Pergilah.
Do you think it is a good idea?
Apa menurutmu kau layak mengatakan itu?
If you think so,
Jika menurutmu begitu,
It's easy to bring you into my car.
sangat mudah untuk membawamu ke mobilku.
(New message. Can't you come yet? I'm waiting for you in front of the Merlion.)
(Pesan baru. Kau ada di mana? Aku sudah menunggumu di depan Merlion.)
Sonoko.
Sonoko.
Shinichi.
Shinichi.
Don't do anything extra.
Tidak perlu ikut campur.
Hey.
Hei.
She is my girlfriend, so what's wrong with you?
Dia adalah pacarku, apa urusanmu dengannya?
Are you?
Apa kau?
Makoto-san, check your e-mail, please.
Makoto-san, setidaknya lihat pesanmu.
Sorry.
Maaf.
I'm not good at tech.
Aku buruk dengan teknologi.
Remember that.
Ingat itu.
Next time, it's my turn.
Berikutnya, adalah giliranku.
Makoto-san
Makoto-san.
I've been scared.
Aku takut sekali.
Sorry I'm late.
Maaf aku telat.
You're so cool.
Kau keren sekali.
I can do it too.
Aku bisa melakukan itu juga.
Hi-yah, hi-yah!
Hi-yah, hi-yah!
(Hey Karate Boy!)
(Hei Anak Karate!)
How great!
Hebat sekali!
(Hey come on!)
(Hei ayolah!)
Sonoko, are you okay?
Sonoko, apa kau baik-baik saja?
Yeah, Makoto-san protected me.
Iya, Makoto-san yang melindungiku.
It's been a while, Kyogoku-san.
Sudah lama sekali, Kyogoku-san.
Good to see you too.
Senang bertemu denganmu lagi.
Are you?
Kau adalah?
Nice to meet you.
Salam kenal.
I'm Shinichi Kudo.
Namaku Shinichi Kudo.
I'm Makoto Kyogoku.
Namaku Makoto Kyogoku.
Hmm?
Hmm?
What's wrong, Makoto-san?
Ada apa, Makoto-san?
Nothing.
Tidak ada.
I just don't feel I meet Kudo-kun for the first time.
Sepertinya aku merasa pernah ketemu dengan Kudo-kun.
It's just your imagination.
Mungkin itu hanya imajinasimu saja.
Now, we've seen the Merlion...
Sekarang, kita sudah melihat Merlion...
Let's go to our hotel.
Ayo kembali ke hotel kita.
Actually,
Sebenarnya...
What?
Apa?
You can't play in the tournament anymore.
Kau tidak bisa ikut di turnamen itu lagi?
We came here to watch your play.
Kami datang kemari untuk melihatmu bertanding.
Sorry.
Maaf.
Today's tournament,
Turnamen hari ini,
A person invited me this match
ada seseorang yang mengundangku ke pertandingan ini,
but,
tapi...
Your sponsor?
Sponsormu?
Yes, the lawyer,
Iya, si pengacara,
Sherilyn Tan
Sherilyn Tan.
She suggested to pay for all my travel and accommodation expenses for the tournament
Dia ingin mensponsori semua biaya perjalananku dan menanggung biaya untuk turnamennya...
but, she suddenly passed away.
tapi, dia tiba-tiba meninggal dunia.
Today, the person concerned told me that
Hari ini, orang yang bersangkutan baru saja memberitahuku...
There was nothing happened, okay.
kalau pertandinganku sudah tidak bisa dilanjutkan.
Oh, no.
Oh, tidak.
I heard that some of the best players in Singapore will be participating
Aku dengar ada yang terbaik dari Singapura yang akan berpartisipasi...
in this tournament
di turnamen ini.
I wanted to fight them once, but
Aku ingin bertarung dengannya untuk sekali saja, tapi...
All right.
Baiklah.
I'll be your sponsor.
Aku akan menjadi sponsormu.
What?
Apa?
Leave it to me.
Serahkan padaku.
- That's Miss Suzuki group. - Uncle? Can you do me a favor?
- Itulah Nona dari grup Suzuki. - Paman? Apa kau bisa membantuku?
(Uncle Jirokichi, Call Ended)
(Paman Jirokichi, Panggilan Berakhir)
It's all right.
Tidak apa-apa.
Makoto-san, I've made you re-enter as an invitee.
Makoto-san, aku telah memasukanmu kembali sebagai peserta.
Really, Sonoko-san?
Benarkah, Sonoko-san?
Yes.
Iya.
I've shared Makoto-san hotel with us.
Aku telah membagi hotel Makoto-san dengan kita.
It's a double date.
Ini jadi kencan ganda.
That's right.
Itu benar.
If it's all settled, let's go back to the hotel.
Karena sudah selesai, ayo kembali ke hotel.
Hurry up and have a beer.
Ayo cepat dan minum bir.
Mouri-san.
Mouri-san.
Are you Kogoro Mouri-san?
Apa kau adalah Kogoro Mouri-san?
Yes.
Benar.
I'm Rishi, a reserve police officer.
Namaku Rishi, seorang perwira polisi sipil.
It's an honor to meet you.
Suatu kehormatan untuk bertemu denganmu.
Well, well, well.
Ya.
Then...
Begitu...
Reserve Police Officer?
Perwira Polisi Sipil?
Yes, sir.
Benar, Pak.
As an expert of criminal behavior psychology.
Sebagai ahli psikologi perilaku kriminal.
I've been joining investigation as an exception.
Aku telah bergabung dengan penyelidikan sebagai pengecualian.
Oh, I see.
Oh, begitu.
I've been waiting for you, Mouri-san.
Aku telah menunggumu, Mouri-san.
Because I've heard you come in Singapore.
Karena aku dengar kau datang ke Singapura.
Were you waiting for me?
Kau telah menungguku?
Yes, sir.
Iya, Pak.
Most of the tourists come here.
Dari semua turis yang datang kemari.
But why me?
Kenapa aku?
Actually, I need your help, Detective Mouri.
Sebenarnya, aku membutuhkan bantuanmu, Detektif Mouri.
We have a case.
Kami mempunyai kasus.
Oh, no, no, no.
Oh, tidak, tidak, tidak.
I'm on vacation.
Aku sedang liburan.
Oh, wait...
Oh, tunggu...
You'd better come with him.
Kau sebaiknya ikut dengannya.
What? Why?
Apa? Kenapa?
Even though he is a reserve police officer,
Walau dia hanyalah seorang perwira polisi sipil.
He might introduce you
Dia mungkin akan mengenalkanmu...
to good, cheap local restaurants.
ke restoran lokal yang murah dan enak.
Or the casino,
Atau mungkin kasino,
You know what I mean...
kau tahu apa maksudku bukan...
Well...
Ya...
It could be...
Sepertinya begitu...
All right.
Baiklah.
I will help you, especially for you.
Aku akan membantumu, khusus untukmu.
- Hey, hey... - Thank you so much.
- Hei, hei... - Terima kasih banyak.
Speaking of Detective Mouri, you are hero in Japan where my father's home country.
Bicara tentang Detektif Mouri, kau adalah seorang pahlawan di Jepang, tempat kelahiran ayahku.
I am also a big fan of you.
Aku juga adalah penggemar beratmu.
Actually, a businessman received something like this
Sebenarnya, seorang pembisnis mendapatkan pesan ini.
Kaito Kid-Kid-sama.
(Aku akan mendapatkan harta karus legendaris, Safir Biru yang dilindungi oleh singa. Kaito Kid) - Kaito Kid - Kid-sama.
(Leon Lowe's House)
(Rumah Leon Lowe)
I received report that Suzuki group
Aku mendapat laporan jika grup Suzuki...
became the sponsor for Kyougoku.
telah menjadi sponsor dari Kyougoku.
Can you beat him?
Apa kau bisa mengalahkannya?
There's no need for concern.
Tidak ada yang perlu dikhawatirkan.
(Hezli Jamaluddin (25), Leon's Head of security)
(Hezli Jamaluddin, 25, Kepala Keamanan Leon)
No matter who I will put him down in one brow.
Tidak peduli siapa dia, aku akan mengalahkannya dengan satu pukulan.
Good to know.
Bagus.
Come in.
Masuklah.
Excuse me.
Permisi.
(Rachel Cheong (28) Leon's Secretary)
(Rachel Cheong, 28, Sekretaris Leon)
Mr. Ramanathan has arrived
Tuan Ramanathan telah tiba...
with someone he would like to introduce.
dengan orang yang ingin dia kenalkan.
It's early.
Cepat sekali.
Please bring him in to the lounge.
Tolong bawa dia ke ruang tunggu.
Understood.
Mengerti.
So how about Kid?
Jadi bagaimana dengan Kid?
Apologies, We are still investigating.
Maaf, kami kasih menyelidikinya.
Among with Sherilyn Tan,
Bersama dengan kasus Sherilyn Tan,
there is Issues with handling information.
ada beberapa masalah dengan mengurus informasinya.
I have a hunch he was behind it.
Aku punya firasat jika dia yang melakukannya.
You take care with it them.
Kau urus mereka.
This is awesome.
Ini luar biasa.
Dad, be quiet.
Ayah, tenanglah.
Oh,  this armor's pretty cool too.
Oh, baju besi ini juga keren.
Are you okay?
Apa kau baik-baik saja?
Whoa!
Whoa!
Dad.
Ayah.
Behave yourself.
Jaga sikapmu.
I'm sorry about my father. - Oh, I'm so sorry.
- Maaf tentang ayahku. - Oh, maafkan aku.
So, who is that Leon Lowe?
Jadi, siapa Leon Lowe itu?
Mr. Lowe is originally a renowned criminal behavior psychologist.
Tuan Lowe dulunya adalah psikolog perilaku kriminal yang terkenal.
He's worked with the police to apprehend a number of violent criminals.
Dia bekerja sama dengan kepolisian untuk menangkap banyak kriminal.
I see.
Begitu.
It's like a Singapore's great detective.
Itu terdengar seperti detektif hebat dari Singapura.
He left the police force two years ago.
Dia keluar dari kepolisian dua tahun lalu,
and he is now the president of a very successful security firm.
dan sekarang dia ada presiden dari perusahaan keamanan yang ternama.
Mr. Lowe taught me
Tuan Lowe mengajariku tentang...
a criminal behavior psychology.
psikologi perilaku kriminal.
I see.
Begitu.
So, Leon has got the notice.
Jadi, Leon telah mendapatkan pesannya.
No, I will explain you step by step.
Tidak, aku akan menjelaskannya secara bertahap.
First, take a look at this.
Pertama, lihatlah ini.
The Kaito Kid's aiming is
Ini adalah yang Kaito Kid incar...
the jewels called the Fist of Blue Sapphire.
permata yang disebut Tinju Safir Biru.
It belongs to a businessman named Zhon Han Chen.
Benda dimiliki oleh seorang pengusaha bernama Zhon Han Chen.
The Kid's notice was delivered to him.
Pesan dari Kid diterima olehnya.
So we should go to this Zhon Han something.
Jadi kita harus pergi ke tempat Zhon Han itu.
The jewels are stored
Permatanya sendiri di simpan...
in the basement of this house.
di ruang bawah tanah dari rumah ini.
The jewels are in here?
Permatanya ada di sini?
Yes.
Benar.
It is the owner's demand.
Ini adalah keinginan dari si pemilik.
The safe here is specially-developed with a state-of-the-art system
Brankas yang ada di sini secara khusus dikembangkan dengan sistem tercanggih...
and better than a bank safe
dan lebih baik dibanding brankas bank.
State-of-the-art.
Tercanggih.
Even the Kid will have some trouble with this time.
Bahkan Kid akan kesulitan dengan ini.
Look who's talking.
Lihat siapa yang berbicara.
What are you talking about?
Apa yang kau bicarakan?
No matter how advanced the safe is.
Tidak peduli seberapa canggih brankasnya.
For Kid-sama, it's a piece of cake.
Bagi Kid-sama, itu akan mudah.
Sonoko.
Sonoko.
You know Ran.
Kau tahu Ran.
Kid-sama's brilliant thievery.
Kid-sama adalah pencuri yang cerdas.
Any woman in the world,
Setiap wanita di dunia,
we cannot stop him to steal our heart.
kami tidak bisa menghentikan dia mencuri hati kami.
Stop Sonoko!
Hentikan Sonoko!
What?
Apa?
Well, except for me and Ran, of course.
Ya, kecuali untuk aku dan Ran tentunya.
Don't you, Ran?
Bukankah begitu, Ran?
Oh, of course!
Oh, tentu saja!
It might be no guarantee of your safety.
Mungkin itu tidak akan menjamin keselamatanmu.
Hey, hey, hey!
Hei, hei, hei!
Nice courtyard
Taman yang cantik.
So-so.
Begitulah.
Nice to meet you all.
Salam kenal semuanya.
My name is Leon Lowe.
Namaku adalah Leon Lowe.
And my bodyguard and head of security.
Dan dia adalah pengawal dan kepala keamananku.
Hezli Jamaluddin, he will join us.
Hezli Jamaluddin, dia akan bergabung dengan kita.
Mr. Kyougoku
Tuan Kyougoku
I was hoping to see you.
Aku ingin bertemu denganmu.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
I do karate too.
Aku juga bisa karate.
I always wanted to have a match with you.
Aku selalu ingin bertarung denganmu.
Oh, you're the great detective, Kogoro-san.
Oh, kau adalah detektif hebat, Kogoro-san.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Terima kasih, terima kasih, terima kasih.
I didn't expect I'm so well known
Aku tidak mengira aku begitu terkanal
even outside Japan.
hingga di luar Jepang.
It's weird.
Itu aneh.
I don't feed anything.
Aku tidak merasakan apa pun.
What is it?
Apa ini?
No way.
Tidak mungkin.
And the high school detective, Shinichi Kudo-san.
Dan si detektif SMA, Shinichi Kudo-san.
Nice to meet you.
Salam kenal.
You look more like a magician than a detective.
Kau lebih terlihat seperti pesulap dibanding detektif.
Your fingers.
Jarimu.
Thin and supple.
Ramping dan lembut.
Even though I'm a detective, I'm more of a player than a fighter.
Walau aku adalah seorang detektif, aku jarang menggunakan ototku.
I'm more playing in here.
Aku lebih sering menggunakan ini.
I see.
Begitu.
Oh, That's,
Oh, itu,
Sonoko Suzuki-san, right?
Sonoko Suzuki-san, benar?
I can't be too careful with this one.
Aku harus waspada dengan orang ini.
You can't come in. Please wait.
Kau tidak boleh masuk. Mohon tunggu.
That's okay, don't bother.
Tidak apa-apa, jangan mengganggu.
Kogoro Mori-san.
Kogoro Mouri-san.
My wife and I are big fan of you.
Istriku dan aku adalah penggemar beratmu.
(Zhon Han Chen (70), Singapore Tycoon)
(Zhon Han Chen, 70, Orang Kaya Singapura)
Whoa!
Whoa!
May I take a photo?
Boleh aku mengambil foto denganmu?
- Photo? Ok, ok. I'm glad. - Sorry he came in all of the sudden.
- Foto? Ok, ok. Dengan senang hati. - Maaf dia tiba-tiba masuk.
It's alright.
Tidak apa-apa.
I would like to show everyone our safe room.
Aku ingin menunjukkan semuanya ruang brankas kami.
That's good.
Itu bagus.
I would love to come along.
Dengan senang hati aku akan ikut.
And the Fist of Blue Sapphire,
Dan Tinju Safir Biru,
I'd like you to take a closer look.
aku ingin kalian melihatnya lebih dekat.
This door leads to top of the safe.
Pintu ini menuju ke atas brankas.
Only a limited number of people can
Hanya beberapa orang tertentu...
open this door.
yang bisa membuka pintu ini.
The walls are made of a heat-resistant alloy.
Dindingnnya terbuat dari bahan anti panas.
It can never be destroyed.
Itu tidak bisa dihancurkan...
Why?
Kenapa?
- Completely shielded from outside interference... - Sorry sorry it's nothing
- Benar-benar terlindungi dari luar... - Maaf maaf bukan apa-apa.
The location of each cargo
Lokasi dari tiap kargo...
is moved periodically.
dipindahkan secara berkala.
This safe is my dream.
Brankas ini adalah impianku.
It's specially made for me.
Ini secara khusus dibuat untukku.
Oh, my God.
Oh, ya Tuhan.
Everyone, please stand back.
Semuanya, mohon mundur.
This is the proof of the Pirate King.
Ini adalah bukti dari Raja Bajak Laut.
It's the Fist of Blue Sapphire.
Permata Tinju Safir Biru.
That's a big blue sapphire. - Can you see, Arthur-kun?
- Itu adalah safir biru yang besar. - Apa kau bisa melihatnya, Arthur-kun?
Yes, thank you.
Iya, terima kasih.
All right.
Baiklah.
As long as it's here.
Selama ia ada di sini.
No matter how hard the Kid tries, he can't touch it.
Tidak peduli seberapa keras Kid mencobanya, dia tidak akan bisa menyentuhnya.
That's not how it works, sir.
Tidak seperti itu cara kerjanya, Tuan.
During the karate tournament starting tomorrow.
Saat turnamen dimulai besok.
The belt will be on display.
Sabuknya akan ditampilkan.
It's a rule.
Itu adalah aturannya.
So, during the tournament.
Jadi, selama turnamen berlangsung,
the belts will be stored in a room at the venue.
akan disimpan di dalam ruangan.
We'll have tighter security, but not as tight as here.
Keamanan kami pasti ketat, walau tidak seketat di sini.
I see.
Begitu...
But there is also security for the stadium.
Tapi ada juga keamanan untuk stadion.
Yes, we should got it any cost.
Iya, kita harus mendapatkannya.
If anything happened to the fist,
Jika terjadi sesuatu dengan permatanya,
you'll be paying hefty compensation fee.
kau akan membayar mahal untuk itu.
You said
Kau mengatakan...
the security is not as good as here.
keamanannya tidak seketat di sini.
So Kid is waiting for the sapphire
Jadi Kid mungkin menunggu safirnya...
to be transferred to the venue.
dpindahkan ke ruangan itu.
You think so?
Menurutmu begitu?
That's right.
Itu benar.
It's too risky to go in here.
Terlalu berisiko untuk datang kemari.
I agree.
Aku setuju.
I'll do what I can to help.
Aku akan melakukan apa pun yang aku bisa.
I'd like to help protect the jewels.
Aku ingin membantu menjaga permatanya.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Easy peasy.
Mudah sekali.
Whoa.
Whoa.
Got fingerprints.
Dapat sidik jarinya.
Too easy?
Terlalu mudah?
I've been waiting for you.
Aku telah menantikanmu.
Kaito Kid.
Kaito Kid.
I can't believe you got this far.
Aku tidak percaya kau sudah sejauh ini.
I'm impressed.
Aku terpukau.
You've got a lot of confidence.
Kau sangat percaya diri ya.
I'm afraid but,
Sayangnya sekali, tapi
I can't let you have the jewels.
aku tidak bisa membiarkanmu mendapatkan permatanya.
I don't want to pay
Aku tidak ingin membayar uang
compensation to Zhon Han Chen.
kompensasi ke Zhon Han Chen.
It's my job to steal that treasure.
Ini adalah tugasku untuk mencuri harta karun itu.
And the harder it is to steal,
Dan semakin sulit untuk dicuri,
the more I'm excited.
semakin aku bersemangat.
It's over.
Berakhir sudah.
I hope you like the taste of Singaporean water.
Aku harap kau menyukai rasa air orang Singapura.
No way.
Tidak mungkin.
I didn't expect you to use a taser.
Aku tidak mengira dia akan menggunakan taser.
Kid.
Kid.
Oh, really?
Oh, yang benar saja?
What the heck?
Apa-apaan?
What happen?
Apa yang terjadi?
It's kid!
Itu Kid!
Don't worry, I'm always-
Jangan khawatir, aku selalu...
You know, the elite is always think of
Kau tahu, yang elit selalu memikirkan...
the worst-case scenario.
skenario terburuknya.
One step ahead.
Satu langkah di depan.
I've got to get out of here.
Aku harus keluar dari sini.
There he is!
Dia ada di sana!
What a thrust.
Pukulan yang kuat sekali.
If I hadn't jumped back, I'd be in trouble.
Jika aku tidak melompat mundur tadi, aku pasti akan dalam bahaya.
Trespassing.
Pencuri.
Right?
Benar?
I mean...
Maksudku ...
What are you doing here?
Apa yang kau lakukan di sini?
I've been invited to train here.
Aku telah diundang untuk berlatih di sini.
but I didn't expect I'd ever match with you.
Tapi aku tidak mengira akan bertarung denganmu.
No, no, no. I don't want to.
Tidak, tidak, aku tidak pernah ingin bertarung denganmu.
No excuse.
Tidak ada alasan.
Are you ready?
Apa kau sudah siap?
Soccer ball.
Sepak bola.
Where the hell is that from?
Dari mana itu asalnya?
Thank you, great detective.
Terima kasih, detektif hebat.
This is awesome.
Ini luar biasa.
I can perfect command with no wind.
Aku bisa terbang tanpa membutuhkan angin.
I have to say thank my grandpa.
Aku harus berterima kasih kepada kakek.
But...
Tapi...
I didn't know he could do that.
Aku tidak tahu dia bisa melakukan itu.
Thanks for the help.
Terima kasih atas bantuannya.
It's a right decision I returned your gear,
Memang tidak salah untuk mengembalikan peralatanmu,
just in case.
hanya untuk berjaga-jaga.
I didn't want to help you.
Aku tidak ingin membantumu.
It doesn't matter.
Tidak masalah.
It's time you told me.
Sudah waktunya kau untuk memberitahuku.
Tell me why you brought me here.
Alasan kau membawaku kemari.
(karate)
(Karate)
Leon's been looking for the Fist of Blue Sapphire
Leon sudah mencari Tinju Safir Biru...
for years.
selama bertahun-tahun.
He was one step away from pulling it out.
Saat dia sudah hampir mendapatkannya.
Zhon Han Chen beat him to it.
Zhon Han Chen yang mendapatkannya duluan.
Apparently,
Sepertinya,
someone leaked to him the location of the sunken ship.
seseorang membocorkan informasi dari lokasi kapal tenggelamnya.
The most suspicious one is Sherilyn Tan.
Yang paling mencurigakan adalah Sherilyn Tan.
Once, she was the legal counsel for Leon's company.
Dulu, dia adalah penasihat hukum di perusahaan Leon.
for a time. But,
Untuk beberapa saat. Tapi,
their relationship deteriorated.
hubungan mereka memburuk.
Rumor has it that she became Kyogoku's sponsor,
Rumor mengatakan itu karena dia menjadi sponsor Kyogoku,
because of Jamaluddin's victory.
karena kemenangan Jamaluddin.
In other words, she wanted to prevent
Dengan kata lain, dia ingin mencegah...
Leon from getting his hands on the jewels.
Leon untuk mendapatkan permata itu.
If that's true,
Jika itu benar,
the rumor that she leaked the information about the sinking ship,
rumor yang mengatakan dia yang membocorkan informasi lokasi kapalnya,
it has the ring of truth.
mungkin itu benar.
Then there was the murder of Sherilyn Tan.
Kemudian ada kasus pembunuhan Sherilyn Tan.
If the leak rumors are true,
Jika semua rumor itu benar,
Leon would have had motive to kill Sherilyn.
Leon akan punya motif untuk membunuh Sherilyn.
What do the police think?
Apa yang polisi pikirkan?
Unfortunately, Leon was taken off
Sayang sekali, Leon dikeluarkan...
the list of suspects.
dari daftar tersangka.
Why?
Kenapa?
Because there is more suspicious suspect.
Karena ada tersangka yang lebih mencurigakan.
Suspect?
Tersangka?
The police haven't released it.
Polisi belum mengumumkannya.
But at the scene of Sherilyn Tan's murder,
Tapi di tempat pembunuhan Sherilyn Tan,
There was a card left.
ada sebuah kartu yang tertinggal.
It was my notice.
Itu adalah kartu pesanku.
That makes sense.
Itu masuk akal.
But why the hell do I have to see
Tapi kenapa aku harus melihat...
this romantic view with this guy?
pemandangan romantis ini dengan orang ini?
I would love to see it with...
Padahal aku ingin melihatnya bersama...
It's time to go back to Arthur Hirai.
Waktunya kembali menjadi Arthur Hirai.
By the way, Arthur is probably from Arthur Conan Doyle.
Omong-omong, nama Arthur mungkin dari Arthur Conan Doyle.
But, why Hirai?
Tapi, dari mana nama Hirai?
Oh, that's?
Oh, itu?
(Ranpo Edogawa (Pen name))
(Ranpo Edogawa (Nama pensil))
(Arthur Conan Doyle) I got it from Taro Hirai, the real name of Ranpo Edogawa.
(Arthur Conan Doyle) Aku mengambilnya dari Taro Hirai, nama asli dari Ranpo Edogawa.
(Arthur Hirai) I got it.
(Arthur Hirai) Aku mengerti.
Anyway, I'm pretty sure it's a trap.
Bagaimanapun, aku yakin ini adalah jebakan.
I know it.
Aku sudah tahu.
That's why I brought you here.
Itulah mengapa aku membawamu kemari.
Great detective.
Detektif hebat.
You're good at this sort of thing.
Kau hebat dalam mengurus hal seperti ini.
I know why.
Aku tahu kenapa.
I just don't like the way you do it.
Aku hanya tidak suka cara kau melakukannya.
The Kid-sama here.
Aku, Kid-sama.
You know, I can't keep quiet.
Tidak akan tinggal diam saja.
You're late.
Kau lama sekali.
I've been waiting a long time.
Aku sudah menunggu lama.
Sorry. Sorry.
Maaf. Maaf.
Look at this.
Lihat ini.
What's a beautiful night view.
Pemandangan yang indah sekali bukan.
It's so romantic.
Itu sangat romantis.
Don't be shy.
Jangan malu begitu.
We're dating, aren't we?
Kita sudah pacaran, bukan?
Oh, yeah.
Oh, iya.
Are we?
Benaran?
Damn.
Sial.
Does't she notice that he is faking?
Kenapa dia tidak tahu jika dia itu palsu?
But if she notice, I won't be able to go back to Japan...
Tapi jika dia mengetahuinya, aku tidak bisa kembali ke Jepang...
(Raffles Hotel)
(Hotel Raffles)
When it comes to Singapore...
Kalau pergi ke Singapura...
Singapore Sling.
harus menjadi orang Singapura.
One more.
Tambah lagi.
Mouri-san?
Mouri-san?
Huh? Are you...?
Huh? Kau adalah...?
Do you mind if I sit here?
Apa kau tidak keberatan jika aku duduk di sini?
Please, please, please.
Silakan, silakan, silakan.
Let's drink together.
Ayo minum bersama.
Actually, I...
Sebenarnya, aku...
Oh Gosh, what have I done?
Oh ya ampun, apa yang telah aku lakukan?
I'm so sorry.
Maafkan aku.
No, no, no. Please don't worry about it.
Tidak, tidak, tidak. Jangan khawatirkan itu.
Mr. Mouri, call for you.
Tuan Mouri, ada panggilan untukmu.
Hmm? Call?
Hmm? Panggilan?
It seems the call is for Mouri-san.
Sepertinya itu panggilan untuk Mouri-san.
For me.
Untuk aku.
Who is it?
Siapa itu?
Mouri-san.
Mouri-san.
There's something I really need to tell you.
Ada sesuatu yang perlu aku beri tahu.
Come here tomorrow.
Datanglah ke sini besok.
What?
Apa?
Damn it.
Sial
Shoot, it's already hung up
Sial, tidak ada siapa-siapa.
Let's get Re-drinking.
Ayo minum-minum lagi.
Who do you think will win?
Siapa yang menurutmu akan menang?
I think Kyogoku.
Menurutku Kyogoku.
He's never lost.
Dia tidak pernah kalah.
I didn't know that.
Benarkah itu?
I've never heard of that.
Aku tidak pernah mendengar itu.
If enough effort is made in the right place and direction,
Jika usaha kerasnya mengenai sasaran dan tepat waktu,
it will pay off.
hasilnya pasti akan terbayarkan.
Do you understand?
Apa kalian mengerti?
Yes, sir.
Iya, pak.
(Karate)
(Karate)
Fast.
Cepat.
This guy Jamaluddin.
Si Jamaluddin ini.
He looks crazy strong.
Terlihat sangat kuat.
He's got heavyweight power, speed, and technique.
Dia mempunyai kekuatan, kecepatan dan teknik.
He's got it all.
Dia mempunyai semuanya.
He looks tough.
Dia terlihat sangat kuat.
That's the Teitan high school karate club captain.
Itulah kapten klub karate SMA Teitan kita.
You know a good thing when you see it.
Kau bisa mengetahuinya hanya dengan melihatnya.
Hey.
Hei.
If the jewel ends up in Kyogoku-san's hands,
Jika permatanya berakhir di tangan Kyogoku-san,
we don't think we'll be able to touch it anymore, right?
sepertinya kita tidak bisa mendapatkannya kembali, bukan?
That's right.
Itu benar.
I don't want to get too close to him.
Aku tidak ingin terlalu dekat dengannya.
Makoto-san is coming.
Makoto-san sudah muncul.
Everyone cheer him up!
Semuanya dukung dia!
Why is that local kid following us?
Kenapa anak lokal itu mengikuti kita?
He takes to me very much.
Dia sangat tertarik denganku.
Bow to each other.
Beri hormat.
Begin.
Mulai.
- Scared - Yay! You're so cool, Makoto-san!
- Mengerikan. - Yei! Kau keren sekali, Makoto-san!
I want to go see him right now.
Aku ingin pergi melihatnya sekarang.
It's my dad.
Ini dari ayahku.
(Incoming Call Dad)
(Panggilan Dari Ayah)
I told you I'm not a suspicious person.
Sudah kubilang aku bukan orang yang mencurigakan.
Dad.
Ayah.
What's going on?
Apa yang terjadi?
Ran
Ran.
Can you explain these guys.
Tolong kau menjelaskannya ke orang ini.
I've taken out all the metal stuff.
Aku telah melepaskan semua benda logam.
But...
Tapi...
No entry.
Tidak boleh masuk.
That's enough.
Sudah cukup.
No!
Tidak!
Damn it, I can't get in here!
Sial, aku tidak bisa masuk!
Are you okay, Mouri-san?
Apa kau baik-baik saja, Mouri-san?
Rishi-san.
Rishi-san.
He is staff member. Please let him in.
Dia adalah anggota staf. Tolong biarkan dia masuk.
Yes sir.
Baik pak.
Thank you, Mr. Rishi.
Terima kasih, Tuan Rishi.
It was nice to meet you again.
Senang bertemu denganmu lagi.
The belt was unveiled at the opening ceremony.
Setelah sabuknya diresmikan di upcara pembukaannya.
It's being kept in the safe in the basement.
Ia akan disimpan di brankas bawah tanah.
I can show you afterwards if you like.
Aku bisa menunjukkannya jika kalian mau.
Anyway, where have you been?
Bagaimanapun, kau dari mana saja?
I've been just on patrol.
Aku baru saja berpatroli.
You must be hungover and oversleep.
Kau pasti mabuk dan telat bangun.
The passcode changes every ten minutes.
Kode sandinya berubah setiap sepuluh menit.
It's managed by a computer.
Itu diatur dengan komputer.
We can get an e-mail.
Kita bisa mendapatkannya lewat e-mail.
Inspector Aidan and myself can receive it.
Hanya Inspektur Aidan dan aku yang bisa mendapatkannya.
And Mr. Lowe, the safe manager.
Dan Tuan Lowe, si manajer brankas.
Only three people.
Hanya tiga orang.
It's just empty room.
Ini hanya ruangan kosong.
No, it's not.
Tidak, tidak sama sekali.
There are weight sensors on the floor, surveillance cameras on the ceiling.
Ada sensor berat di lantai, dan kamera pengintai di langit-langit.
And the venue is surrounded by police officers.
Dan tempat ini dijaga oleh petugas polisi.
I'm sure.
Aku yakin.
The Kid would do nothing about it.
Kid tidak bisa berbuat apa-apa.
Mouri-san, you can't smoke in here.
Mouri-san, kau tidak boleh merokok di sini.
Oh, sorry.
Oh, maaf.
Hmm?
Hmm?
I was so drunk. I've completely forgot it.
Aku terlalu mabuk. Aku jadi melupakan ini.
She gave me this last night at the bar.
Dia memberikannya kepadaku kemarin di bar.
She said she wanted to talk to me.
Dia mengatakan dia ingin berbicara denganku.
This is Leon-san's secretary's card.
Ini adalah kartu sekretaris Leon-san.
What? Oh, really?
Apa? Oh, benarkah?
Actually, I was too drunk to remember.
Sebenarnya, aku terlalu mabuk untuk mengingatnya.
How did you know it?
Bagaimana kau bisa tahu?
It's got the logo of Leon-san's company on it.
Itu ada logo dari perusahaan Leon-san.
Logo mark?
Logo?
3 p.m.
Pukul 3.
Back of National Stadium.
Di belakang Stadion Nasional.
Meet in front of the door 3. It says.
Temui aku di pintu depan pada pukul 3. Katanya.
It also says, TELL NO ONE.
Ia juga mengatakan, jangan beri tahu siapa pun.
Okay, 3 p.m., it means...
Baik, pukul 3, berarti...
It's very soon.
Itu sebentar lagi.
Mouri-san.
Mouri-san.
It's rude to keep a lady waiting.
Tidak sopan untuk membiarkan gadis menunggu.
Hmm?
Hmm?
That was a really good match.
Itu pertandingan yang bagus.
I'm looking forward to the semifinal and finals tomorrow.
Aku menantikan semi final dan finalnya besok.
Thank you very much.
Terima kasih banyak.
Your strength is special.
Kekuatanmu itu spesial.
Would you be interested in being my bodyguard?
Apa kau tertarik untuk menjadi pengawalku?
No thank you, sir.
Tidak, terima kasih pak.
Wait a minute.
Tunggu sebentar
It was joking, of course.
Tentu saja, aku hanya bercanda.
Actually, I have one question for you.
Sebenarnya, aku punya satu pertanyaan untukmu.
Tell me.
Beri tahu aku.
What is the purpose of your fists?
Apa tujuan dari tinjuanmu itu?
In the pursuit of strength, what's beyond that?
Mengejar kekuatan, apa lagi setelah itu?
What is it that drives you?
Apa yang mendorongmu?
Can't you answer that?
Apa kau tidak bisa menjawab itu?
An imperfect fist with no purpose is dangerous.
Tinju tanpa sebuah tujuan itu berbahaya.
It makes you unhappy... and people around you.
Itu akan membuatmu... dan orang di sekitarmu tidak senang.
You'll make everyone unhappy.
Kau akan membuat semua orang sedih.
People around me are unhappy.
Orang-orang di sekitar diriku akan bersedih.
Yes.
Benar.
For example, person who you love.
Sebagai contoh, orang yang kau sukai.
I'm sure you have someone like that.
Aku yakin kau memiliki orang seperti itu.
Your fist may cause trouble,
Tinju milikmu akan menjadi masalah,
and hurt your love one.
dan melukai orang yang kau sayangi.
What would you do if that happened?
Apa yang akan kau lakukan jika itu terjadi?
I'm looking forward to tomorrow's match, too.
Aku menantikan pertandingan besok.
Anything else?
Apa ada lagi?
Good job.
Kerja bagus.
Sonoko-san.
Sonoko-san.
You haven't come to see me for long, so I've come to see you.
Aku menunggumu cukup lama, jadi aku datang untuk mencarimu.
I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
Maaf aku membuatmu menunggu lama.
Let's go lunch.
Ayo pergi makan siang.
There's a restaurant I want to go.
Ada restoran yang ingin aku kunjungi.
Sorry, Sonoko.
Maaf, Sonoko.
Why don't you two go eat together?
Bagaimana kalau kalian pergi berdua saja?
Why?
Kenapa?
I'm so sorry.
Maafkan aku.
Shinichi is unlikely to leave here because of the jewel guard.
Shinichi ingin tetap di sini untuk menjaga permatanya.
So, I don't think I can leave here, too.
Jadi, aku mungkin tidak bisa meninggalkannya.
I see.
Begitu.
Well then, it's no choice... let's go.
Kalau begitu, tidak ada pilihan lain... ayo.
Makoto-san
Makoto-san...
Okay.
Baik.
See you later, Ran.
Sampai jumpa, Ran.
See you later.
Sampai jumpa.
I want you to have lots of food.
Aku ingin kau makan yang banyak.
Thank you very much.
Terima kasih banyak.
Now be alert and look everywhere.
Sekarang tetap waspada dan perhatikan sekitar.
If you see anything unusual. Report it.
Jika kau melihat sesuatu yang mencurigakan, segera laporkan.
And act immediately and-
Dan langsung beraksi dan...
Are you okay?
Apa kau baik-baik saja?
I'm so sorry.
Maafkan aku.
I'm sorry too.
Maafkan aku juga.
Inspector Aidan.
Inspektur Aidan.
Sorry I couldn't help but notice.
Maaf aku tidak bisa membiarkannya.
I'm sorry what?
Maaf apa?
There you go,
Sudah,
Keep up the good work,
semangat kerjanya.
Yes mam!
Baik nyonya!
Everything okay with the safe?
Semua baik-baik saja dengan brankasnya?
Yes sir everything is alright.
Iya Pak semua baik-baik saja.
Excuse me I'm so sorry.
Maafkan aku.
What's the matter?
Ada apa?
Inspector Aidan Is calling you come quick.
Inspektur Aidan sedang memanggil kalian untuk ke sana, cepat.
B, But...
T-Tapi...
I look after this place.
Aku akan menjaga tempat ini.
O, okay.
B-Baik.
Will be back soon thank you.
Kami akan segera kembali, terima kasih..
Well...
Ya...
I'll take the treasure.
Aku akan mengambil harta karunnya.
I got it.
Dapat.
What's wrong with it?
Ada apa dengan ini?
A dead body.
Mayat.
Rachel?
Rachel?
Omg, I gotta get out of here.
Oh ya Tuhan, aku harus pergi sekarang.
Hmm? Something letters...
Hmm? Ada semacam pesan...
Oh, shit.
Oh, sial.
Stop right there.
Berhenti di sana.
Drop the gun down.
Jatuhkan pistolnya.
Kid you are under arrest.
Kid kau akan ditangkap.
What?
Apa?
Goddamn it, how much longer she keep me waiting?
Sialan, berapa lama dia ingin membuatku menunggu?
Rachel-san.
Rachel-san.
Give her ten more minutes,
Berikan dia 10 menit lagi,
What the hell?
Apa-apaan?
Is it the Kid?
Apakah itu Kid?
Wait a minute.
Tunggu sebentar.
He's here.
Dia ada di sini.
Holy shit!
Ya ampun!
But if I can get out of here, I'll be fine.
Tapi jika aku bisa keluar dari sini, aku akan baik-baik saja.
I can't believe they're so many.
Aku tidak percaya ada banyak sekali polisinya.
Hey, wait.
Hei, tunggu.
Damn!
Sial...
Go! Arrest him! At any cost!
Pergi! Tangkap dia! Apa pun yang terjadi!
Yes sir.
Baik pak.
Are they okay?
Apa mereka baik-baik saja?
Hey! I was looking for you, Mouri-san.
Hei! Aku sedang mencarimu, Mouri-san.
What a mess we've gotten ourselves into.
Sepertinya terjadi kekacauan di sini.
I didn't expect the Kid to show up in broad daylight like this.
Aku tidak mengira Kid akan muncul siang bolong seperti ini.
Don't worry.
Jangan khawatir.
This great detective, Kogoro Mouri.
Detektif hebat ini, Kogoro Mouri.
I'll start tracking him right away.
Akan segera melacaknya.
This is not the time.
Bukan waktunya untuk itu.
Something terrible has happened.
Sesuatu yang buruk terjadi.
Please come to the safe right now.
Tolong pergi ke brankasnya sekarang.
Look!
Lihat!
There's a giant bird in the sky!
Ada burung besar di langit!
Come this far, they won't catch
Sudah sejauh ini, mereka tidak akan...
W,what's that.
A-Apa ini.
The victim is Mr. Lowe's secretary.
Korbannya adalah sekretaris Tuan Lowe.
Rachel-san.
Rachel-san.
Okay.
Baik.
Have you checked the security cameras?
Apa kau sudah memeriksa kameranya?
Nothing.
Tidak ada apa-apa.
It's been hacked and transmitted
Kameranya telah diretas dan dirusak...
the unattended footage repeatedly.
dengan rekaman yang diulang-ulang.
So do you think who did it.
Jadi apa kau tahu siapa pelakunya?
Of course we do.
Tentu saja.
We're doing everything we can to track him down.
Kami melakukan semua yang kami bisa untuk memburunya.
track him down?
Memburunya?
In other words.
Dengan kata lain.
I'm pretty sure it's the Kid.
Aku yakin pelakunya adalah Kid.
Whatever, it's your fault
Apa pun itu, ini adalah salahmu...
for not disabling the security system, Kid.
karena tidak mematikan sistem keamanannya, Kid.
Hey, actually, at that time
Hei, sebenarnya, pada saat itu...
Rachel-san was supposed to be at the stadium
Rachel-san seharusnya ada di stadion.
to meet this old guy.
Untuk menemui orang tua ini.
Why was she in the safe?
Kenapa dia pergi ke brankas?
Well, I agree.
Ya, aku setuju.
According to the cops in front of the safe.
Menurut polisi di depan brankas.
She's there to tell him that Inspector Aidan had an errand for him.
Dia memberitahunya jika Inspektur Aidan menyuruhnya untuk pergi menemuinya.
It was urgent.
Itu adalah keadaan darurat.
I'm guessing that took priority.
Mungkin karena itu lebih prioritas.
And then there was that whole mess.
Dan kemudian terjadi kekacauan ini.
But I've never heard of the Kid killing anyone.
Tapi aku tidak pernah mendengar Kid membunuh siapa pun.
You can't just barge in.
Kau tidak boleh masuk sembarangan.
What the hell?
Apa-apaan ini?
(she)
(She)
Hey, look at this blood letters.
Hei, lihat tulisan dengan darah ini.
Hey!
Hei!
Stay out of this, kid.
Menjauh dari sini, bocah.
Look at this.
Lihat ini.
He've been completely trapped in their trap.
Dia benar-benar sudah terjebak...
Kid.
Kid.
Good job.
Kerja bagus.
It's getting more interesting.
Ini menjadi semakin menarik.
That's Sonoko-san's selection.
Itu adalah pilihan Sonoko-san.
The chicken rice and watermelon juice were both good.
Nasi hainan dan jus semangkanya juga enak.
It was really delicious.
Ini benar-benar enak.
Right?
Benarkan?
What is that?
Ada apa?
Well, now we're full...
Ya, sekarang kita sudah kenyang...
Makoto-san
Makoto-san.
I have somewhere to go.
Aku ingin pergi ke suatu tempat.
I'll come with you wherever you go.
Aku ikut denganmu ke mana pun itu.
This looks bad.
Ini terlihat buruk.
Hey girl,
Hei gadis,
what you gonna do about this?
apa yang akan kau lakukan dengan ini?
You're the one who hit me.
Kau yang menabrakku.
Hah? I don't know what you mean?
Hah? Aku tidak mengerti apa maksudmu?
Come here!
Kemarilah!
There may be others hiding out here.
Mungkin masih ada yang lainnya yang sedang bersembunyi.
Sonoko-san.
Sonoko-san.
Stay close to me.
Tetap berada di dekatku.
Yeah.
Baik.
Your fist may cause trouble,
Tinjumu akan mejadi masalah,
and hurt your love one.
dan melukai orang yang kau sayangi.
Sonoko-san.
Sonoko-san.
Found it.
Ketemu.
Please help me.
Tolong aku.
Sonoko-san!
Sonoko-san!
She alright?
Apa dia baik-baik saja?
I'm calling the ambulance.
Aku akan panggil ambulan.
Is she foreigner?
Apa dia orang asing?
Sonoko-san!
Sonoko-san!
Sonoko-san, Sonoko-san, Sonoko-san!
Sonoko-san, Sonoko-san, Sonoko-san!
What's the status of her injuries?
Bagaimana dengan kondisinya?
They said it's not life-threatening.
Mereka mengatakan nyawanya tidak terancam.
She's sleeping now, so she'll stay in the hospital tonight.
Dia sedang tertidur sekarang, jadi dia akan tinggal di rumah sakit malam ini.
They're doing examines tomorrow.
Mereka akan melakukan pemeriksaan besok.
What a relief.
Syukurlah.
But a vicious hit-and-run...
Tapi itu tabrak lari yang kejam...
- It's unforgivable. - It's my fault.
- Tidak bisa dimaafkan. - Ini salahku.
It's my fault.
Ini salahku.
Sonoko-san...
Sonoko-san...
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Maaf membuat kalian menunggu lama.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Maaf aku telat.
Thank you for your time.
Terima kasih sudah meluangkan waktumu.
What's the status of the investigation?
Bagaimana hasil penyelidikannya?
Yes, sir.
Iya, Pak.
The scene was a deserted back street. No witnesses.
Tempat kejadian itu di jalan belakang. Tidak ada saksi.
Well, technically, there was a person,
Ya, secara teknis, di sana ada orang,
but he was caught off guard and knocked unconscious
tapi saat dia lengah dan dipukul pingsan...
when the police car was taken from someone.
saat mobil polisinya dicuri oleh seseorang.
I hope I'm not interrupting you.
Aku berharap aku tidak mengganggu.
Mr. Lowe
Tuan Lowe...
What brings you here?
Apa yang membawamu kemari?
As soon as I heard about the accident, I've hurried to come here.
Setelah aku mendengar kecelakaannya, aku bergegas kemari.
Sonoko was still asleep.
Sonoko sedang tidur sekarang.
Could you hand this to her, please?
Boleh tolong berikan ini kepadanya?
Thank you very much.
Terima kasih banyak.
It looks like my worries
Sepertinya yang aku khawatirkan...
have come true.
telah menjadi nyata.
The gods of battle is giving you a test.
Dewa pertarungan sedang mengujimu.
You don't have enough mindset
Kau belum punya cukup prinsip...
for shaking your fist, yet.
untuk memberikan tinjumu.
Well, I'm giving you a charm.
Ya, aku akan memberikan sebuah jimat.
It's like a miçanga.
Ini seperti miçanga.
When it breaks...
Saat itu putus...
the proof of being recognized by God as you have mindset.
itu adalah bukti jika Dewa telah mengakui kau mempunyai prinsip.
But if you shake your fist before it breaks...
Tapi jika kau mengeluarkan tinjuanmu sebelum itu putus...
You know that, right?
Kau tahu maksudnya, bukan?
Ouch.
Aduh.
That was a nasty hit.
Kau memiliki banyak luka.
It's nothing like this.
Ini bukan apa-apa.
Oh, man, they shoot with no hesitation.
Oh, ya ampun, mereke menembak tanpa ragu.
They got me this time.
Mereka mendapatkanku kali ini.
They're blaming you for Rachel-san's murder.
Mereka menyalahkanmu atas pembunuhan Rachel-san.
It's all a setup.
Itu semua adalah jebakan.
It's all a trick to get you to take the blame.
Itu semua adalah jebakan agar kau menerima semua dosanya.
It's like magic.
Itu seperti sihir.
I was not even there, but
Aku bahkan tidak ada di sana, tapi...
the audience sees me as the killer.
para penonton melihatku sebagai seorang pembunuh.
As if I was there.
Seakan-akan aku ada di sana.
I mean, if you switch perspectives.
Maksudku, jika kau mengubah sudut pandangnya.
I can see the trick.
Aku bisa melihat triknya.
Yeah, it's the magician who makes you feel as if there's something inside his fist.
Iya, itu adalah pesulap yang membuatmu berpikir jika ada sesuatu di dalam kepalannya.
That's what magicians do.
Itulah yang dilakukan para pesulap.
What's in his fist before he open it.
Apa isi dari kepalannya yang belum dibukanya.
We detective guess the answer correctly.
Kita para detektif yang menebaknya.
Tell me what's in the fist, great detective.
Beri tahu aku apa isinya, detektif hebat.
What's in that mysterious fist called "murder"?
Apa isi dari kepalan misterius yang disebut "pembunuhan?"
Jesus.
Ya Tuhan.
Hey, little boy. You're not home yet, are you?
Hei, nak. Kau masih belum pulang?
Can I spend the night tonight?
Apakah aku boleh menginap malam ini?
What, at my place?
Apa, di tempatku?
I'm all alone when I get home.
Aku akan sendirian jika pulang ke rumah.
After what just happened, I'm scared.
Setelah apa yang terjadi, aku takut.
I think it'll make my dad feel better
Kupikir ayahku akan lebih tenang jika...
If I'm with you, Rishi-san.
mengetahui aku bersamamu, Rishi-san.
Hmm...
Hmm...
Two nights in a row with him.
Dua malam berturut-turut dengannya...
in the same room would be awful.
di kamar yang sama itu sangat buruk.
Wow.
Wow.
Are these all from Rishi-san's father?
Semua ini dari ayahnya Rishi-san?
He gave you all these?
Dia memberikanmu semua ini?
Yes, my dad was an oceanographer.
Iya, ayahku adalah seorang ahli laut.
He passed away five years ago.
Beliau meninggal lima tahun yang lalu.
In the process of his research, he found ruins that had sunk into the sea.
Dalam proses penelitiannya, dia menemukan reruntuhan yang tenggelam di dalam laut.
You must be very proud of him.
Kau pasti sangat bangga dengannya.
Yeah.
Iya.
Well, I've still got some work to do.
Ya, aku masih ada kerjaan.
Arthur-kun, you can go to bed first?
Arthur-kun, apa kau bisa tidur duluan?
Okay.
Baik.
Hey, Rishi-san...
Hei, Rishi-san...
What are those red crosses on this map?
Apa tanda merah di peta ini?
These are the places where pirates attacked ships.
Itu adalah tempat terjadi serangan bajak laut.
Are there still pirates?
Apa masih ada bajak laut?
Yes, there used to be many near Singapore.
Iya, ada banyak di dekat Singapura.
There used to be a lot of them.
Dulu lebih banyak lagi
I'm not worried about pirates.
Aku tidak mengkhawatirkan tentang bajak lautnya.
I'm more worried about the murders now.
Aku lebih khawatir tentang pembunuhannya.
And the Kaito Kid.
Dan Kaito Kid.
I borrowed the files from Inspector Aidan.
Aku meminjam dokumennya dari Inspektur Aidan.
I'll be up all night tonight.
Aku akan lembur malam ini.
I'm sorry, but Rishi-san,
Maafkan aku, tapi Rishi-san,
I'll let you sleep it off.
aku akan membiarkanmu tertidur.
Hey, what's that?
Hei, apa itu?
Did you wear  that?
Apa yang kau pakai itu?
Sonoko-san, are you awake?
Sonoko-san, kau sudah bangun?
Actually I've been awake for a while.
Sebenarnya aku sudah bangun dari tadi.
I'm glad, really.
Syukurlah.
Is that some kind of lucky charm?
Apa itu adalah semacam jimat keberuntungan?
Yeah.
Iya.
Something like that.
Semacam itu.
Phew.
Phew.
No, you need to get some rest.
Tidak, kau harus istirahat.
I'm not sleepy at all.
Aku tidak ngantuk sama sekali.
I've come all this way to Singapore. It's boring.
Aku sudah datang jauh-jauh ke Singapura. Ini membosankan.
Don't push yourself. It's not good for you.
Jangan memaksakan dirimu. Itu tidak baik.
You should stay in bed tonight.
Kau harus beristirahat malam ini.
I've been asking to you...
Aku selalu ingin bertanya denganmu...
Why don't you take off that bandage on your left eyebrow?
Kenapa kau tidak melepaskan perban di alis mata kirimu?
It's nothing, really.
Bukan apa-apa, benaran.
I thought we were not supposed to meet
Kupikir kita tidak akan bertemu...
until everything was done.
hingga semuanya selesai.
You bragged your plan was perfect.
Kau membual jika rencanamu itu sempurna.
But are you totally sure
Tapi apa kau benar-benar yakin?
You look tough but you're actually a coward.
Kau terlihat kuat tapi sebenarnya pengecut.
Now watch your mouth.
Sekarang jaga mulutmu.
I always keep promises
Aku selalu menepati janji.
I do.
Selalu.
If someone done to me, I'll give it back.
Jika seseorang menjebakku, aku akan membalasnya.
That's my style.
Itulah caraku.
(In the semifinals, Makoto Kyogoku versus Tang Lee.)
(Di semi final, Makoto Kyogoku melawan Tang Lee.)
(Due to Kyogoku's withdrawal.)
(Karena Kyogoku mengundurkan diri.)
(Tang Lee will advance to the final.)
(Tang Lee akan maju ke babak berikutnya.)
Damn it!
Sialan!
I didn't ask for this.
Aku tidak meminta ini.
He withdrew from the tournament?
Kau mengundurkan diri dari turnamen?
Why, because of me?
Kenapa, karena aku?
We can't be sure that the people who attacked us
Kita tidak tahu pasti jika orang-orang yang menyerang kita
won't attack us again.
tidak akan menyerang lagi.
I can't leave Sonoko-san's alone.
Aku tidak bisa membiarkan Sonoko-san sendirian.
It's my fault after all.
Lagi pula ini adalah salahku.
You should go to the tournament.
Kau harus pergi ke turnamen.
You have someone you want to fight.
Kau mempunyai lawan yang menunggumu.
I do.
Iya.
But I couldn't protect Sonoko-san.
Tapi aku jadi tidak bisa melindungi Sonoko-san.
I still feel I'm missing something.
Aku masih merasa kekurangan sesuatu.
I'm sure you're missing something.
Aku yakin kau masih kekurangan sesuatu.
What?
Apa?
You're full of secrets, Makoto-san.
Kau penuh dengan rahasia, Makoto-san.
Secrets?
Rahasia?
About the miçanga and the bandage.
Tentang miçanga dan perban itu.
You never tell me.
Kau tidak pernah memberitahuku.
No, this is really...
Tidak, ini benar-benar...
Get out.
Keluar.
Yeah.
Baik.
I don't want to be protected by a man
Aku tidak ingin dilindungi oleh pria...
who is full of fake.
yang penuh dengan kebohongan.
I was really worried about you yesterday, okay?
Aku benar-benar mengkhawatirkanmu kemarin, oke?
I've been trying to reach you.
Aku sudah mencoba untuk menghubungimu.
I'm sorry.
Maafkan aku.
I got caught up in chasing the Kid.
Aku terlalu fokus untuk mengejar Kid.
That's the Moonlight Magician.
Dia adalah Pesulap Cahaya Bulan.
Even this Shinichi Kudo can't catch him.
Bahkan Shinichi Kudo ini tidak bisa menangkapnya.
Hi, Arthur-kun.
Hai, Arthur-kun.
Hello. - Ouch.
- Halo. - Ouch.
Is your friend Sonoko Nee-san okay?
Apa temanmu Sonoko Nee-san baik-baik saja?
I went to the hospital a while ago.
Aku baru saja pergi ke rumah sakit.
The doctor said she's fine.
Dokter mengatakan dia baik-baik saja.
She'll be out of the hospital this afternoon and back at the hotel.
Dia bisa keluar dari rumah sakit sore ini dan kembali ke hotel.
I'm so happy to hear that.
Syukurlah kalau begitu.
Thanks for worrying about her.
Terima kasih sudah mengkhawatirkannya.
It's better get back to the hotel.
Lebih baik sekarang kembali ke hotel.
I need to pack my luggage for the trip home.
Aku harus menyusun barangku untuk perjalanan pulang.
Are you sure you leave Sonoko Nee-san and him?
Apa kau yakin akan meninggalkan Sonoko Nee-san dan dia?
Yeah, I thought I'd leave them alone for a while.
Iya, aku berpikir akan membiarkan mereka berdua untuk sementara.
Those two seemed to be in some kind of trouble.
Mereka berdua sepertinya sedang ada masalah.
And Kyogoku-san had to withdrawal his match.
Dan Kyogoku-san harus mengundurkan diri.
What? Shinichi?
Apa? Shinichi?
So, did you get anything last night? Great detective.
Jadi, apa kau mendapatkan sesuatu semalam? Detektif hebat.
According to the case files I found at Rishi-san's house.
Menurut dokumen kasus yang aku temukan di rumah Rishi-san.
According to eyewitness accounts, Sherilyn-san was stabbed
Menurut beberapa saksi mata, Sherilyn-san tidak ditusuk...
not at the mall where she collapsed.
di pusat perbelanjaan tempat dia terjatuh.
But it would be in an elevator in Tower 3.
Tapi di lift di Menara 3.
Why bother in the elevator?
Tapi kenapa di lift?
If it's fail, nowhere to run away.
Jika dia gagal, dia tidak bisa melarikan diri.
She was stabbed in her back with a store-bought knife.
Belakangnya ditusuk dengan pisau yang dibeli di toko.
Then move to the shopping mall as it is
Kemudian memindahkannya ke pusat perbelanjaan...
And immediately after she collapsed,
dan setelah dia terjatuh,
her car exploded in the underground parking lot.
mobilnya meledak di tempat parkir.
As a result, the entire hotel loses power.
Hasilnya, seluruh hotel mengalami pemadaman listrik.
That's why all footage from the security cameras
Itulah mengapa semua kamera keamanan...
inside the hotel has gone.
di dalam hotel mati.
What's curious is that Leon was there.
Yang mencurigakan adalah Leon ada di sana.
He booked his own room
Dia memesan kamarnya sendiri...
and Sherilyn-san's room as well.
dan kamar Sherilyn-san juga.
But when she was murdered,
Tapi saat dia dibunuh,
he was in another elevator.
dia berada di elevator yang lainnya.
Many witnesses testified that.
Banyak saksi yang mengatakan itu.
Because of that he proved his alibi.
Karena dia membuktikan alibinya.
So he is out of the equation.
Jadi dia bebas dari pertanyaan.
Exactly.
Benar sekali.
Speaking of which,
Bicara tentang itu,
why was Leon was carrying a suitcase?
kenapa Leion membawa koper pada saat itu?
Oh, yeah, of course the police checked inside.
Oh, iya, tentu saja polisi memeriksanya.
But it was empty.
Tapi isinya kosong.
The suitcase was in the shop for repairs.
Kopernya ada di toko perbaikan.
He just picked it up.
Dia baru saja mengambilnya.
The shop near the hotel,
Tokonya ada di dekat hotel,
we've confirmed that they received the order from him.
kita sudah mengkonfirmasikan jika itu adalah pesanannya.
Perfect alibi.
Alibi yang sempurna.
Only one thing left to do.
Hanya tersisa satu hal lagi.
This.
Ini...
Why was this left at the crime scene?
Kenapa ini ada di tempat kejadian?
Why involve me in this?
Kenapa melibatkan aku dengan ini?
He even went to the trouble of painting it with blood.
Dia bahkan repot-repot melukisnya dengan darah.
Also...
Dan juga...
he's trying to pin Rachel-san's murder
dia ingin menyalahkan pembunuhan Rachel-san...
on you.
ke dirimu.
The murder weapon was the same knife used to kill Sherilyn-san.
Senjata pembunuhannya sama dengan Sherilyn-san.
Rachel-san was in the safe before I got there.
Rachel-san ada di dalam brankas sebelum aku di sana.
She had been placed in the pedestal.
Dia telah diletakkan di sana.
But to get into the room, she had to get past the guards.
Tapi untuk memasuki ruangan, dia harus melewati penjaga...
and a number of security devices.
dan beberapa sistem keamanan.
The person who could get past the guards
Orang yang bisa melewati itu...
without touching the sensors.
tanpa harus menyentuh sensor.
It's not me.
Itu bukan aku.
It's Leon Lowe, after all.
Lagi pula, itu adalah Leon Lowe.
Leon is the one who manage the safe.
Leon lah yang mengatur brankas itu.
He knows the security system inside and out.
Dia tahu sistem keamanan dalam dan luarnya.
Moreover the belt was delivered to the stadium was
Terlebih lagi sabuknya dibawa ke stadion...
yesterday morning.
saat kemarin pagi.
Rachel-san was confirmed alive
Rachel-san dikonfirmasi masih hidup...
until the night before last.
hingga malam kemarin.
So the crime was most likely committed from that night
Jadi kejahatannya mungkin dilakukan dari malam itu...
to before the belt was brought in.
hingga sebelum sabuknya dipindahkan.
But for what?
Tapi untuk apa?
Why would he need to murder his own secretary?
Kenapa dia membunuh sekretarisnya sendiri?
Maybe that's the motive.
Mungkin itu adalah motifnya.
Rachel-san was trying to tell Mister something.
Rachel-san mencoba untuk memberitahu Paman sesuatu.
The only clue we have left is that blood letters.
Petunjuk yang tersisa adalah pesan darah itu.
She.
She.
Who's that?
Siapa itu?
No, no, no.
Tidak, tidak, tidak.
Something extraordinary is about to happen.
Sesuatu di luar nalar akan terjadi.
I can't think straight.
Aku tidak bisa berpikir jernih.
Even the great detective can't help it.
Bahkan detektif hebat juga kesulitan.
Then let's take a break for a while.
Kalau begitu kita istirahat sebentar.
By the way, which in my fist, what's inside?
Omong-omong, tangan mana yang ada isinya?
Coconut water in your left fist.
Air kelapa ada di tangan kirimu.
Correct.
Benar.
How did you know that?
Bagaimana kau bisa tahu?
You bought it earlier.
Kau barusan membelinya.
You've been spotted.
Aku sudah ketahuan.
Magic.
Sulap.
It's the magician who makes you feel as if there's something inside his fist.
Pesulap yang membuatmu berpikir jika ada sesuatu di dalam kepalannya.
That's what magicians do.
Itu yang biasa dilakukan pesulap.
What's in his fist before he open it.
Apa isi kepalannya sebelum dia membukanya.
We detective guess the answer correctly.
Kita detektif menebak jawabannya dengan benar.
I see.
Begitu.
By the way, Miss Sonoko.
Omong-omong, Nona Sonoko.
She's in trouble with that karate guy?
Apa dia bermasalah dengan orang karate itu?
Apparently.
Sepertinya begitu.
Well, caught up in a brawl and a car accident  on the travel
Ya, terlibat perkelahian dan kecelakaan saat perjalanan...
I guess that makes her mental unstable.
kurasa itu membuat mentalnya kurang stabil.
I see.
Jadi begitu.
What?
Apa?
Causing Sonoko got Injured,
Karena menyebabkan Sonoko terluka,
shakes Kyogoku-san emotionally.
membuat Kyogoku-san jadi emosional.
To Jamaluddin's victory,
Untuk kemenangan Jamaluddin,
The biggest obstacle was Kyogoku-san.
tantangan terbesarnya adalah Kyogoku-san.
I see.
Begitu.
So, Leon set up the accident.
Jadi, Leon menyebabkan kecelakaan itu.
Just as he planned, Kyogoku-san withdrew from the tournament.
Seperti yang direncanakannya, Kyogoku-san mengundurkan diri dari turnamen.
The championship belt is now definitely
Sabuk kejuaraannya sudah pasti dimiliki...
Jamaluddin's.
Jamaluddin.
Which means it's in the hands of his employer.
Yang berarti itu ada di tangan karyawannya.
Leon's hand.
Di tangan Leon.
Along with the Fist of Blue Sapphire.
Bersama dengan Tinju Safir Biru.
But why does Leon care so much about the Fist of Blue Sapphire?
Tapi kenapa Leon begitu peduli dengan Tinju Safir Biru?
Why is Leon so obsessed with that?
Kenapa dia terobsesi dengan itu?
I think I've got a clue.
Sepertinya aku punya petunjuk.
The man Leon met with at dawn.
Orang yang Leon temui saat fajar.
Can you identify this guy?
Bisa kau mengidentifikasi orang ini?
It's not impossible.
Itu memungkinkan.
You said to professor I'm going to Hokkaido.
Kau mengatakan pada profesor "Aku akan pergi ke Hokkaido."
just out of the blue and long silence.
secara tiba-tiba.
What are you doing?
Sekarang apa yang sedang kau lakukan?
Sorry, Haibara. I've got a lot going on.
Maaf, Haibara. Banyak yang terjadi di sini.
You guys, be quiet.
Kalian, diam dulu.
Yes, sir.
Baik...
What the hell.
Dasar.
You're involved in a case again, aren't you?
Kau terlibat dengan kasus lagi, bukan?
Actually, you're right.
Sebenarnya, iya kau benar.
I've just sent you the photos data Kid took.
Aku baru saja mengirimkan foto yang Kid ambil.
Kid?
Kid?
Did you say "Kid"?
Kau baru saja mengatakan "Kid?"
Really? Did Kaito Kid appear?
Benarkah? Apakah Kid muncul?
It's Conan-kun, isn't it?
Itu pasti Conan-kun, bukan?
Conan-kun is in Hokkaido, right?
Conan-kun sedang ada di Hokkaido, bukan?
What's the Kid stealing?
Apa yang akan Kid curi?
Maybe a hand-carved bear?
Mungkin patung beruang kayu?
Sapporo Ramen noodle?
Ramen Sapporo?
He wouldn't steal something like that.
Dia tidak mungkin mencuri hal seperti itu.
Ai-chan.
Ai-chan.
Can I talk to Conan-kun on the phone?
Boleh aku berbicara dengan Conan-kun?
Me too.
Aku juga.
Sorry, kids are here.
Maaf, anak-anak lagi di sini.
I'll tell you more when I get home.
Aku akan cerita semuanya saat aku pulang.
I need you to identify the man in the photos.
Aku membutuhkanmu untuk identifikasi orang di foto itu.
Okay, okay, okay.
Baik, baik, baik.
So, you're really okay?
Jadi, apa kau akan baik-baik saja?
I guess so.
Sepertinya begitu.
I'm sure there's no point in telling you.
Aku yakin tidak ada gunanya untuk memberitahumu.
Don't overdo it.
Jangan memaksakan diri.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
It's OK now.
Sudah tidak apa-apa sekarang.
So, what shall we do now? Great detective.
Jadi, apa yang kita lakukan sekarang? Detektif hebat.
Wait and see.
Tunggu dan lihat.
What Leon will do now that he's got the Fist of Blue Sapphire.
Apa yang akan Leon lakukan saat dia mendapatkan Tinju Safir Biru.
But first, see Mister.
Tapi pertama, lihat Paman.
Oh, wait a minute.
Oh, tunggu sebentar.
(The John Han Cup Karate Champion is...)
(Juara Turnamen Karate John Han adalah...)
(Jamaluddin)
(Jamaluddin)
So, what do you think of my city plan?
Jadi, bagaimana dengan rencana kotaku?
We cannot accept your proposal.
Kami tidak bisa menerima proposalmu.
Why?
Kenapa?
You lose nothing with this plan.
Kau tidak akan rugi apa-apa dengan rencana ini.
It's also benefit to the country.
Itu juga akan menguntungkan negara.
It's too hasty.
Itu terlalu terburu-buru.
If you proceed much development,
Jika kau melakukan begitu banyak perkembangan,
some may be forced out of their homes.
beberapa orang mungkin akan kehilangan tempat tinggalnya.
We can give them another place.
Kita bisa memberikan mereka tempat tinggal lainnya.
The plan is perfect!
Rencananya sangat sempurna!
You are too young.
Kau masih terlalu muda.
Learn some more and come back.
Belajar lagi dan kembali nanti.
Old fool.
Orang tua bodoh.
Your era is now at an end.
Era kalian akan berakhir sekarang.
I will build a new city.
Aku akan membangun kota baru.
Hand in the air!
Angkat tangan!
Okay okay.
Baik, baik.
You and I are well connected, aren't we?
Kau dan aku sangat terikat, bukan?
If this plan succeeds, we will be
Jika rencana ini berhasil, kita akan menjadi...
partners.
rekan.
I'm looking forward to working with you.
Aku menantikan bisa bekerja sama denganmu.
You've helped me a lot.
Kau telah banyak membantuku.
When I was taken to the police station on suspicion of theft,
Setelah aku dibawa ke kantor polisi karena dicurigai mencuri,
but you protected me.
tapi kau melindungiku.
That was the first time.
Itu baru awalnya.
And a lot of things after that.
Dan kemudian banyak hal terjadi setelahnya.
Since I found out that you are that Reijiro Nakatomi.
Setelah aku mengetahui kau adalah Reijiro Nakatomi.
The Japanese shipping magnate,
si tokoh dari pengiriman Jepang,
Juzo Nakatomi. You are son of him.
Juzo Nakatomi. Kau adalah anaknya.
Please don't mention my father's name.
Tolong jangan menyebutkan nama ayahku.
Oh, I beg your pardon.
Oh, maafkan aku.
In any case, everything will change tonight.
Bagaimanapun, semua akan berubah malam ini.
Why don't you come and watch it up close?
Bagaimana jika kau ikut denganku dan melihatnya lebih dekat?
Come with me.
Ikut denganku.
To witness a page in the history of
Untuk menyaksikan perubahan sejarah dari...
Singapore.
Singapura.
Huh?
Huh?
Sorry, Mister.
Maaf, Paman.
What's going on?
Apa yang terjadi?
Stop it, pervert!
Hentikan itu, mesum!
This is it.
Ini dia.
Nakatomi.
Nakatomi.
Nakatomi?
Nakatomi?
Does it mean Nakatomi Shipping?
Apakah maksudnya Pengiriman Nakatomi?
Probably.
Mungkin.
Hey, Mister.
Hei, Paman.
I'll borrow this.
Aku pinjam ini sebentar.
Didn't you say "Mister"?
Apakah kau memanggilku "Paman?"
That kid.
Anak itu.
Why are you leaving Japan so suddenly?
Kenapa kau tiba-tiba meninggalkan Jepang?
It's a vacation. Vacation.
Ini adalah liburan. Liburan.
You went to Singapore five years ago, didn't you?
Kau pergi ke Singapura lima tahun lalu, bukan?
(Alleged Bribery of Politicians: Direct interview President Nakatomi)
(Dugaan Suap Politisi: Wawancara langsung Presiden Nakatomi)
Ah since then
Ah sejak itu...
(President Nakatomi Shipping, Reijiro Nakatomi 39) So what?
(Presiden Pengiriman Nakatomi, Reijiro Nakatomi 39) Jadi kenapa?
President Nakatomi is currently under suspicion of bribery by the Criminal Investigation...
President Nakatomi saat ini diduga melakukan penyuapan oleh Investigasi Kriminal...
The guy at Merlion Park?
Itu adalah orang di Taman Merlion?
That karate guy beat him up.
Yang dihajar oleh orang karate itu.
Haibara?
Haibara?
Have you found out who that guy is?
Apa kau sudah tahu siapa itu?
Yeah, kind of.
Iya, sepertinya.
His name is Eugene Lim.
Namanya adalah Eugene Lim.
What a surprise. He's a pirate.
Yang mengejutkan. Dia adalah seorang bajak laut.
A pirate?
Bajak laut?
There's been a recent sighting in Singapore.
Ada beberapa saksi melihatnya di dekat Singapura.
You're reliable, Haibara.
Kau benar-benar bisa diandalkan, Haibara.
You flatter me, so...
Kau memujiku, jadi...
you still want me to find out something, right?
masih ada lagi yang ingin kau minta, bukan?
Y, yeah...
I-Iya...
Have you ever heard of Reijiro Nakatomi?
Apa kau pernah dengar Reijiro Nakatomi?
Nakatomi Shipping?
Pengiriman Nakatomi?
I know him.
Aku tahu dia...
I want to know the status of the ships owned by Nakatomi Shipping.
Aku ingin tahu status dari kapal yang dimiliki Pengiriman Nakatomi.
Just the ships in and around Singapore.
Hanya kapal yang ada di dekat Singapura.
In near Singapore, there are two cargo ships
Di dekat Singapura, ada dua kapal kargo...
and one tanker.
dan satu kapal tanker.
I'm a little concerned about the tanker.
Aku sedikit khawatir dengan yang tanker.
The tanker is off its scheduled route.
Kapal tankernya keluar dari rute yang dijadwalkan.
That's the one.
Yang itu.
Send me the info on that tanker.
Beri aku informasi dari tanker itu.
All right. I'll contact you again.
Baiklah. Aku akan menghubungimu lagi.
Please.
Tolong.
What's wrong with the tanker?
Ada apa dengan yang tanker?
It's the word "she" that Rachel left.
Itu adalah kata "she" yang ditinggalkan Rachel.
She's also the word for ship.
She bisa diartikan sebagai kapal.
Is it true what you said on the phone?
Apa yang kau katakan di ponsel itu benar?
Everything that's happening right now,
Semuanya sedang terjadi sekarang,
Mr. Lowe has plotted.
itu direncanakan Tuan Lowe.
You should explain it to me.
Kau harus menjelaskannya padaku.
It all started with something Zhon Han Chen found,
Itu dimulai saat Zhon Han Chen menemukan,
the Fist of Blue Sapphire.
TInju Safir Biru.
He mounted it in a champion belt for a karate tournament.
Dia memasangnya di sabuk kejuaraan untuk turnamen karate.
The winner will get it.
Pemenangnya yang akan mendapatkannya.
Leon-san made Jamaluddin-san enter the match
Leon-san membuat Jamaluddin berpartisipasi turnamen itu
and tried to get the jewels.
dan mencoba untuk mendapatkan permatanya.
However, he was interrupted unexpectedly.
Namun, dia tiba-tiba diganggu.
400 undefeated karate fighter.
Oleh petarung dengan 400 pertarungan yang tidak terkalahkan.
Makoto Kyogoku had entered the tournament.
Makoto Kyogoku telah berpartisipasi dalam turnamen.
The one who invited him.
Yang mengundang dia...
That's the murdered Sherilyn Tan-san.
adalah Sherilyn Tan-san yang telah terbunuh.
Even if that's the motive,
Walau itu adalah motifnya,
Mr. Lowe has an alibi.
Tuan Lowe tetap punya alibi.
When she was stabbed,
Saat dia ditusuk,
he was in a different elevator.
dia berada di lift yang berbeda.
Here's the truth.
Ini adalah kebenarannya.
After her meeting with Leon by the pool,
Setelah bertemu dengan Leion di kolam,
she got on the elevator
dia naik lift...
to get back to her room.
untuk kembali ke kamarnya.
But the room she was staying in.
Tapi kamar yang dia tinggali.
Tower 3, where she was staying, was on the 16th floor.
Menara 3, di mana dia tinggal, ada di lantai 16.
Because of the hotel structure, she always had to change elevators
Karena struktur hotelnya, dia harus selalu pindah lift...
on the 34th floor.
di lantai 34.
She was on her way back to her room,
Saat dia berjalan kembali ke kamarnya,
She was taken to another room.
Dia dibawa ke kamar lainnya...
By his secretary Rachel.
Oleh sekretarisnya Rachel.
Rachel was her accomplice.
Rachel adalah kaki tangannya.
No way.
Tidak mungkin.
Leon was there that day.
Leon ada di sana pada hari itu.
The room he book just to enter the poolside guest restaurant was
Kamar yang dia pesan hanya untuk memasuki retoran tamu di tepi kolam...
on the 34th floor.
ada di lantai 34.
And when
Dan saat...
Leon came down, and in that room,
Leon turun, dan ada di ruangan itu,
He stabbed Sherilyn-san to death.
dia menusuk Sherilyn-san hingga meninggal.
He put her body in his suitcase.
Dia memasuki tubuhnya ke dalam kopernya.
After that, Rachel and Leon got into separate elevators.
Setelah itu, Rachel dan Leon naik lift yang berbeda.
I guess he used a kind of
Kurasa dia menggunakan semacam...
trick knife.
trik pisau.
But the blood was Sherilyn-san's own.
Tapi darahnya adalah milik Sherilyn-san.
Rachel fakes the being stabbed and collapses.
Rachel berpura-pura telah ditusuk dan terjatuh.
Shortly thereafter,
Setelah itu,
the explosion knocks out the power.
ledakan terjadi dan memadamkan listriknya.
It was all done in secret.
Itu semua dilakukan secara rahasia.
Oh, no.
Oh, tidak.
Rachel knows Leon's true plan.
Rachel tahu rencana Leon yang sebenarnya.
She was so terrified that.
Dia sangat ketakutan hingga...
She was going to tell Detective Mouri everything.
dia ingin memberitahu semuanya ke Detektif Mouri.
Leon found out about it.
Leon mengetahui hal itu.
The woman who came to the safe, Rachel-san,
Wanita yang datang ke ruang brankas, Rachel-san,
was the Kid in disguise.
adalah Kid yang sedang menyamar.
The Kid was used by him.
Kid telah digunakan olehnya...
in Leon-san's plot.
untuk rencana Leon.
The real Rachel-san had already been murdered.
Rachel-san yang asli sudah dibunuh...
and put in the pedestal.
dan di letak di sana.
I read that Kid was going to disguise himself as Rachel-san.
Aku merasa Kid akan menyamar sebagai Rachel-san.
He predicted that Kid was coming in disguise as Rachel-san
Dia memprediksi jika Kid akan datang dengan menyamar sebagai Rachel-san...
to create his alibi and
dan menjadikannya sebagai alibinya dan...
make the incident look like Kid did it.
membuatnya seperti Kid yang melakukannya.
How is that possible?
Bagaimana itu mungkin?
So, How about Rishi-san...
Jadi, bagaimana dengan Rishi-san...
Who would you disguise yourself as to be safe?
Kau ingin menyamar menjadi siapa untuk pergi ke brankas dengan aman?
Oh, right.
Oh, iya.
No matter how well I disguise, it's useless if I bump into the real person.
Tidak peduli seberapa handal aku menyamar, itu tidak berguna jika aku menemui orang aslinya.
I'd prefer someone who knows
Aku lebih memilih seseorang yang tahu...
where he or she will be at what time in advance.
di mana dia atau akan berada di waktu itu.
I see, Rachel was going to meet Mouri-san at 3:00 PM.
Begitu, Rachel akan menemui Mouri-san pada pukul 3.
that's why
Itulah mengapa...
Kid's coming to the safe.
Kid datang ke brankas.
He'll disguise himself as someone who will never come
Dia menyamar sebagai orang yang tidak akan muncul di sana...
That's how Leon-san predict it.
Begitu cara Leon-san memprediksinya.
The Kid fell right into his trap.
Kid terjatuh ke dalam jebakannya.
So, tell me.
Jadi, beri tahu aku.
What is Mr. Lowe attempting to?
Apa yang Tuan Lowe coba lakukan?
It's all part of a ridiculous plan.
Itu semua adalah bagian dari rencana konyolnya.
Leon has been in contact with a Pirate Chief,
Leon telah menghubungi Ketua bajak Laut,
Eugene Lim.
Eugene Lim.
The writing on the pedestal at the scene of Rachel's murder.
Pesan yang tertulis di tempat pembunuhan Rachel.
Her dying message is "She".
Pesan kematiannya adalah "She."
And what Rachel had secretly entrusted to Detective Mouri was
Dan apa yang Rachel secara rahasia percayakan kepada Detektif Mouri adalah...
Nakatomi Shipping medal.
Medali Pengiriman Nakatomi.
All related to ships.
Semua berhubungan dengan kapal.
What does that got to do with anything?
Apa maksudnya dengan itu?
Rishi-san
Rishi-san.
This is sent to me from Tokyo by the detective brother.
Ini dikirim dari saudara detektif.
It's a route analysis of
Ini adalah analisis jalur dari...
all the Nakatomi-owned ships in this area.
semua kapal Nakatomi di daerah ini.
One of the tankers has veered off course.
Salah satu kapal tankernya telah keluar jalur.
If they keep going like this, they'll end up in Marina Bay.
Jika mereka terus begini, mereka akan berakhir di Marina Bay.
Leon-san plotting to use pirates
Leon-san berencana untuk menggunakan bajak laut...
to drive the tanker into city.
untuk mengemudikan kapal tankernya ke kota.
First of all, why would he need to do that?
Pertama, kenapa dia ingin melakukan itu?
Why is that?
Kenapa itu?
I don't know what Leon-san would say it, but...
Aku tidak tahu apa yang akan Leon-san katakan, tapi...
but if this city were destroyed and needed to rebuild it.
tapi jika kota ini hancur dan harus dibangun ulang kembali.
I'm sure it would cost a fortune.
Aku yakin itu akan memakan banyak uang.
The reason why Leon-san obsessed on the Fist of Blue Sapphire was
Alasan kenapa Leon-san terobsesi dengan Tinju Safir Biru karena...
because he needed it in exchange for controlling the pirates as he wanted.
dia membutuhkan itu untuk bisa mengendalikan bajak laut semaunya.
But the pirates escape the attention of the police.
Tapi para bajak laut menjauh dari perhatian polisi.
They scatter all over the place.
Mereka menyebar di seluruh tempat.
How did he get in touch with them?
Bagaimana dia bisa menghubunginya?
The Merlion.
Merlion.
There was an incident with the Merlion spouting red water.
Ada kejadian saat Merlion mengeluarkan air merah.
It was reported worldwide.
Itu dilaporkan di seluruh dunia.
It must have caught the pirates' attention.
Itu pasti memancing perhatian bajak laut.
That must have been the signal of action.
Itu pasti adalah sinyal untuk beraksi.
But now,
Tapi sekarang,
If we don't do something now, it'll be too late.
jika kita tidak melakukan sesuatu, itu akan terlambat.
Even if you say so, it's not up to me.
Walau kalian berkata begitu, itu bukan tergantung aku.
I need more evidence to move the police.
Aku membutuhkan lebih banyak bukti untuk menggerakkan polisi.
We don't have time.
Kita tidak punya banyak waktu.
Is there any other way?
Apa ada cara lain?
Yes, we can talk to Mr. Zhon Han Chen.
Iya, kita bisa bicara dengan Tuan Zhon Han Chen.
He's got connection to the military and the police.
Dia mempunyai jaringan dengan militer dan polisi.
I'm sure he'll help us.
Aku yakin dia akan membantu kita.
One more thing, Rishi-san
Satu lagi, Rishi-san...
What?
Apa?
If the tanker crashes into the city as planned.
Jika kapal tanker menabrak kota seperti yang direncanakannya.
Where do you think Leon-san will be?
Di mana menurutmu Leon-san akan berada?
Let me think...
Biar kupikirkan...
He's a cautious man.
Dia adalah pria yang berhati-hati.
He'll probably be somewhere far away watching.
Dia mungkin berada di tempat yang jauh untuk melihatnya.
Maybe he won't be in Singapore anymore.
Mungkin dia tidak ada di Singapura lagi.
I'll hurry.
Aku harus cepat.
Okay. Thank you.
Oke. Terima kasih.
Dad, where is he?
Ayah, di mana dia?
The show's about to start.
Acaranya sudah mau dimulai.
Shinichi's gone, too.
Shinichi menghilang juga.
I don't know how I got involved in all this.
Aku tidak tahu bagaimana aku bisa terlibat dengan ini semua.
I wonder if it was Leon who left my card at the scene of Sherilyn-san's murder.
Aku penasaran apakah Leon yang meninggalkan kartuku di tempat pembunuhan Sherilyn-san.
Was it really Leon?
Apakah itu benar-benar Leon?
No.
Tidak.
The card was found on the elevator.
Kartunya ditemukan di lift.
It was found until long after the crime scene inspection had begun.
Itu ditemukan beberapa lama setelah penyelidikan dimulai.
Do you wonder why?
Apa kau penasaran kenapa?
Whoa.
Whoa.
The latest tanker track analysis.
Analisis jalur tanker terbarunya.
Huh?
Huh?
The tanker's heading to the hotel.
Kapal tankernya mengarah ke hotel.
Ran, pick up the phone.
Ran, angkat teleponnya.
Coming this way!
Mengarah ke sini!
Hey, Ran, having fun?
Hei, Ran, bersenang-senang?
Dad, where are you?
Ayah, kau ada di mana?
Ugh? I don't know where I am but,
Ugh? Aku tidak tahu aku di mana. Tapi,
I can see a huge ship.
aku bisa melihat kapal besar.
Hey Dad...
Hei Ayah...
Are you top of the hotel?
Apa kau ada di atas hotel?
(Ran Mouri) Hello, hello, hello
(Ran Mouri) Halo, Halo, Halo...
Can we make it?
Apa kita sempat?
I think so.
Sepertinya.
Sonoko-san. Sonoko-san.
Sonoko-san. Sonoko-san.
What?
Apa?
Something's happened outside.
Terjadi sesuatu di luar.
I think we should leave the hotel.
Kurasa kita harus pergi dari hotel.
Yes, sir.
Baik, Pak.
Yeah, okay.
Iya, baik.
Who was that?
Siapa itu?
The police officer.
Dari petugas polisi.
If I go out,
Jika aku pergi keluar,
I might be targeted again. They might try to kill me again.
aku mungkin menjadi sasaran lagi. Mereka mungkin akan mencoba untuk membunuhku.
He told me to stay in my room.
Dia menyuruhku untuk tetap di ruanganku.
They're sending a guard.
Mereka akan mengirimkan penjaga.
B,But...
T-Tapi...
Don't worry, I'll stay here.
Jangan khawatir, aku akan tetap di sini.
Okay.
Baik.
I can't get near the hotel with this crowd.
Aku tidak bisa mendekati hotel dengan keramaian ini.
I'll take my chances.
Mau bagaimana lagi.
It's kid!
Itu adalah Kid!
It's kid. Kid here.
Itu adalah Kid. Kid ada di sini.
It's a private party.
Ini adalah pesta pribadi.
What the hell?
Apa-apaan?
Sleeping Kogoro...
Kogoro Tukang Tidur...
I really don't know just about him.
Aku tidak tahu dengan dia.
I can't get her!
Aku tidak bisa menghubunginya!
Oh no!
Oh tidak!
Where is he, Dad?
Di mana dia, Ayah?
Look,
Lihat,
the city will be born again
kotanya akan lahir kembali...
with my hands.
dengan tanganku.
Why are you?
Kenapa kau?
Wait!
Tunggu!
What a surprise.
Mengejutkan sekali.
I didn't know you were capable of so much.
Aku tidak tahu kau bisa sampai sejauh ini.
I couldn't predict it.
Aku tidak bisa memprediksinya.
Rishi.
Rishi.
I'll admit it.
Aku akan mengakuinya.
Yes, this is all my plan.
Iya, ini adalah rencanaku.
Let's have a little talk.
Mari kita berbincang-bincang.
Please put it down.
Tolong turunkan senjatamu.
I think you've got it all wrong, Mr. Lowe.
Kurasa kau salah paham, Tuan Lowe.
What?
Apa?
Freeze!
Jangan bergerak!
There's no one here.
Tidak ada orang di sini.
We are stopping ship now.
Kami akan menghentikan kapalnya sekarang.
The tanker stopped.
Kapal tankernya berhenti.
Kid.
Kid.
Let's leave the police handle this.
Biarkan polisi yang mengurus ini.
Yeah.
Iya.
The tanker!
Kapal tankernya!
What happened?
Apa yang terjadi?
I'll be quiet.
Aku akan diam.
Please don't shoot me.
Tolong jangan tembak aku.
Help me.
Tolong aku.
Please don't kill me.
Tolong jangan bunuh aku.
Rishi-kun!
Rishi-kun!
I never thought you shoot us.
Aku tidak pernah mengira kau akan mengeluarkan tembakan.
(Jamaluddin! )
Jamaluddin!
W wait!
T-Tunggu!
Jamaluddin, what are you thinking?
Jamaluddin, apa yang kau pikirkan?
The only reason work for you
Satu-satunya alasan aku bekerja denganmu...
with the fight again Kyogoku.
supaya bisa bertarung dengan Kyogoku.
I have no such reason anymore.
Aku tidak ada alasan lain.
What?
Apa?
Mr. Lowe.
Tuan Lowe.
I'm afraid but I think you've lost a bit of your touch.
Sepertinya kau sudah semakin tumpul.
You're not the one running the world.
Bukan kau lagi yang mengendalikan dunia ini.
It's me.
Tapi aku.
No, you
Tidak, kau!
Wait, wait, wait.
Tunggu, tunggu, tunggu.
I'll give you this.
Aku akan memberikanmu ini.
There's a jewel inside.
Ada permata di dalamnya.
It's good deal, Rishi-kun.
Ini penawaran yang bagus, Rishi-kun.
Kaito Kid.
Kaito Kid.
Why are you here, Arthur-kun?
Apa yang kau lakukan di sini, Arthur-kun?
To get to the roof, I have to change elevator on the 34th floor.
Untuk menuju ke atap, aku harus ganti lift di lantai 34.
Hey!
Hei!
Wait.
Tunggu.
Are they
Apakah mereka...
heading to the Marina Bay Sands?
mengarah ke Marina Bay Sands?
What are you doing?
Apa yang kau lakukan?
I was trying to catch
Aku sedang mencoba untuk menangkap...
the two ringleaders.
kedua pemimpin kelompoknya.
I know you are faking it!
Aku tahu kau berpura-pura!
Rishi Ramanathan.
Rishi Ramanathan.
I know you're the mastermind behind all this.
Aku tahu kau adalah dalang dari ini semua.
My first question was,
Pertanyaan pertamaku adalah...
the notice the Kid left at the scene.
pesan Kid yang tertinggal di tempat kejadian.
The police officer found out the notice shortly after
Petugas polisi menemukannya sesaat setelah ...
you arrived at the scene, right?
kau tiba di tempat kejadian, bukan?
And just now.
Dan baru saja...
When I asked you where Leon-san would be,
Saat aku bertanya di mana Leon-san akan berada,
my suspicions about you were confirmed.
kecurigaanku terhadapmu telah dipastikan.
What?
Apa?
A man as conceited as Leon-san.
Seorang yang sombong seperti Leon-san.
Will he flee abroad just as he was about to
Akan melarikan diri saat dia akan...
complete his plan?
menyelesaikan rencananya?
I'm sure he is looking at the place
Aku yakin dia akan mencari tempat...
with the best view.
terbaik untuk menyaksikan hasil karyanya.
You can't be unaware of that.
Kau tidak mungkin tidak mengetahui itu.
I'm surprised. You tested me.
Aku tercengang. Kau mengujiku.
It all started five years ago.
Itu semua di mulai lima tahun lalu.
Your father's accident was the beginning of your plan.
Kecelakaan ayahmu adalah awal mula dari rencanamu.
Suspect admits killing oceanographer
Tersangka mengakui membunuh seorang ahli kelautan.
After initial denial
Setelah membantah di awal.
Probably
Mungkin...
It is also five years ago Nakatomi-san visited Singapore, isn't it?
Itu juga terjadi di lima tahun lalu saat Nakatomi-san mengunjungi Singapura, bukan?
I...
Aku...
Leon-san caught the culprit.
Leon-san menangkap pelakunya.
Sherilyn-san defended him,
Sherilyn-san membelanya,
and made him plead guilty.
dan membuatnya mengaku bersalah.
I don't think it's all just a coincidence.
Kupikir itu semua bukanlah sebuah kebetulan.
What do you mean?
Apa maksudmu?
It was a trick to get tankers
Itu adalah sebuah trik untuk mendapatkan kapal tanker...
owned by Nakatomi Shipping.
yang dimiliki oleh Pengiriman Nakatomi.
The whole thing was a setup.
Semua hal itu telah diatur.
And there was another trick.
Dan ada trik lainnya.
You must've noticed that.
Kau pasti telah mengetahuinya.
I thought it was an accident, too, at first.
Pada awalnya, aku mengira itu adalah kecelakaan juga.
But when I was sorting through my father's belongings,
Tapi pada saat aku menyusun barang milik ayahku,
I found out that while he was investigating underwater ruins,
aku menemukan kalau saat dia sedang meneliti reruntuhan bawah laut,
he accidentally discovered a sunken ship
dia tidak sengaja menemukan kapal tenggelamnya...
that was most likely to have the proof of the Pirate King,
yang kemungkinan besar adalah bukti dari Raja Bajak Laut,
the Fist of Blue Sapphire.
Tinju Safir Biru.
That's probably why he killed my father first.
Itu mungkin alasan dia membunuh ayahku.
He didn't want him to get to the jewel first.
Dia tidak ingin permatanya ditemukan duluan.
Help!
Tolong!
Someone push in the back!
Seseorang mendorongku...
Help is on the way!
Bertahanlah!
Hurry!
Cepat!
Helping.
Membantu.
Because he knew my father had a strong sense of justice,
Karena dia tahu ayahku punya rasa keadilan yang kuat,
He was sure my father would definitely go to help.
dia yakin ayahku pasti akan menolongnya.
What the hell, Leon?
Apa-apaan itu, Leon?
Get off me!
Lepaskan aku!
Rishi-kun, you've got some wrong.
Rishi-kun, kau salah paham.
Your father's culprit is in prison.
Pelaku pembunuh ayahmu ada di penjara.
I had my doubts about my father's death.
Aku meragukan penyebab kematian ayahku.
I became your apprentice in Singapore.
Aku menjadi muridmu di Singapura.
I became a reserve police officer.
Aku menjadi perwira polisi sipil.
And I started looking into the accident.
Dan aku mulai menyelidiki kecelakaannya.
I approached Sherrilyn Tan, who was lawyer in charge of the case.
Aku menghampiri Sherrilyn Tan, yang merupakan pengacara dari kasus itu.
I asked her if we could use Reijiro's case to blackmail Leon.
Aku bertanya kepadanya apakah kami bisa menggunakan kasus Reijiro untuk memeras Leon.
She gave me the lowdown.
Dia memberitahuku dengan singkat.
And Rachel.
Dan Rachel.
Yes, through her,
Iya, melaluinya,
I knew everything about you guys.
aku tahu semua tentang kalian.
Then why did you put up the Kid notice?
Kalau begitu kenapa kau meletakkan pesan Kid?
Tell me why.
Beri tahu aku kenapa.
The Fist of Blue Sapphire
Tinju Safir Biru...
And a murder he did not get involved at all.
dan pembunuhan yang tidak dia lakukan.
Those two things would definitely lure the Kid.
Dua hal itu pasti akan memancing Kid.
And he would thwart your plans.
Dan dia akan merusak rencanamu.
The high-school detective's appearance was unexpected.
Aku tidak mengira detektif SMA juga akan datang.
But he's done his job.
Tapi dia sudah melakukan dengan baik.
Nakatomi-san.
Nakatomi-san.
I heard that Leon protected you
Aku dengar jika Leon melindungimu
from being accused of stealing.
dari tuduhan pencurian.
But, was that really a coincidence?
Tapi, apakah itu benar-benar sebuah kebetulan?
Think about it.
Pikirkan itu.
Maybe...
Mungkin...
All of it.
Semuanya.
You.
Kau.
You've done your research, Rishi-kun.
Kau telah menelitinya dengan baik, Rishi-kun.
Where am I? I think...
Di mana aku? Kurasa...
Dad
Ayah.
Ran. What?
Ran. Apa?
What is it?
Ada apa?
Dad
Ayah.
Ran
Ran.
Over!
Mundur!
Everycrew tell the chopper too!
Semua kru dan helikopter juga!
What is it with you guys?
Siapa kalian?
Well, Rishi-kun...
Ya, Rishi-kun...
Unfortunately, the tables have turned
Sayang sekali, situasi telah terbalik...
(ユージーン　計画は失敗したが)
Eugene, rencananya sepertinya gagal.
You can take this jewel.
Kau bisa mengambil permata ini.
Take care of everyone here.
Urus semua orang di sini.
Yes.
Baik.
What are you doing?
Apa yang kau lakukan?
Don't move.
Jangan bergerak.
Help!
Tolong!
Now that I have the jewel I have no need for you.
Sekarang aku sudah memiliki permatanya, kau tidak perlukan lagi.
What?
Apa?
I have no time for your nonsense.
Aku tidak punya waktu untuk omong kosongmu.
I am known to the break promises.
Aku dikenal sebagai pengingkar janji.
It's just there was more a lucrative offer.
Hanya saja ada penawaran yang lebih menggiurkan.
What do you want?
Apa yang kau inginkan?
What a smart boy you are!
Kau benar-benar bocah yang pintar!
That's right.
Itu benar.
The daughter of Suzuki group is in this hotel.
Putri dari grup Suzuki ada di hotel ini.
If we kidnap her the ransom will be huge.
Jika kami menculiknya, uang tebusannya pasti tinggi.
Hasn't she already evacuated?
Bukankah dia sudah dievakuasi?
She's still in her suite.
Dia masih ada di ruangannya.
I called her and not to leave the room.
Aku menghubunginya supaya tidak pergi dari ruangannya.
W,what, Makoto-san?
A-Apa, Makoto-san?
Excuse me.
Maafkan aku.
The elevators were all stopped.
Liftnya semua tidak bisa digunakan.
Let's get out of here.
Ayo kita keluar dari sini.
There come on!
Di sana! Ayo!
Don't shoot! You hit her!
Jangan tembak! Kau bisa mengenainya!
Makoto-san, what's this all about?
Makoto-san, apa yang terjadi?
Look.
Lihat.
In the end, everything will be exactly as I envisioned it.
Pada akhirnya, semuanya akan sesuai dengan yang aku bayangkan.
This city will be burned to the ground and reborn.
Kota ini akan terbakar dan terlahir kembali.
You'll never see it.
Kau tidak akan pernah melihatnya.
What? They're going to locket us?
Apa? Mereka akan mengunci kita?
Hey, you!
Hei, kau!
Damn!
Sial!
Take that!
Rasakan itu!
Get down now!
Menyerahlah!
Makoto-san!
Makoto-san!
What? What?
Apa? Apa?
Get them!
Kejar mereka!
- Open! - Brat!
- Bukan! - Bocah!
Come, come, come
Ayo, ayo, ayo
What is going on here?
Apa yang terjadi di sini?
I don't know.
Aku tidak tahu.
Most of the pirates now in the hotel.
Hampir semua bajak laut ada di hotel sekarang.
Just what is going on inside?
Apa yang sebenarnya terjadi di dalam?
It's dangerous you too, please give back.
Di sini berbahaya juga, tolong kembalilah.
You okay?
Kau baik-baik saja?
Ah, yeah
Ah, iya.
If we don't do something, they'll really destroy the city.
Jika kita tidak melakukan sesuatu, mereka benar-benar akan menghancurkan kota.
Damn it. Is there got to be a better way?
Sial. Apa ada cara yang lebih baik?
We could use that.
Kita bisa menggunakan itu.
Got it.
Mengerti.
Kid.
Kid.
Are you sure about that?
Apa kau yakin dengan itu?
Of course I am.
Tentu saja.
That's the going kid!
Itu orangnya!
Shoot him down.
Tembak dia.
Boss we can't hit him!
Bos kami tidak bisa mengenainya!
(Clever bird.)
Dasar burung menyebalkan.
Hey, before we do that.
Hei, sebelum kita melakukan itu.
We've got to deal with those pirates.
Kita harus menghadapi bajak laut itu dulu.
We only have one Card gun left.
Hanya tersisa satu pistol kartu lagi.
We still have one bullet.
Kita masih punya satu peluru.
We've got a chance to turn the tables on them.
Kita punya kesempatan untuk membalik situasi.
I see.
Jadi begitu.
We'll go in.
Kita maju.
Wait!
Tunggu!
Makoto-san.
Makoto-san.
Get down!
Tangkap mereka!
Stay back!
Mundurlah!
He is
Dia
mine.
milikku.
Kid.
Kid.
Take me to the bow.
Bawa aku ke haluan.
I know.
Aku tahu.
Ran, stay back.
Ran, mundurlah.
Ran.
Ran.
Come on!
Ayo!
What the hell is going on here?
Apa-apaan yang sedang terjadi di sini?
Shinichi's voice.
Suara Shinichi.
Are you okay?
Apa kau baik-baik saja?
Arthur, why are you here?
Arthur, kenapa kau ada di sini?
I was worried about you.
Aku khawatir denganmu.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Where the hell is he?
Di mana dia?
I'm glad you're okay.
Syukurlah kau baik-baik saja.
What?
Apa?
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Makoto-san.
Makoto-san.
Kid got jewell.
Kid mendapatkan permatanya.
Can you hit him down?
Apa kau bisa menembaknya?
Okay boss.
Siap bos.
Damn stay still.
Sial tetap di sana.
Take this!
Rasakan ini!
Hit it?
Kena?
I'm okey, Sonoko-san.
Aku tidak apa-apa, Sonoko-san.
Oh no!
Oh tidak!
What?
Apa?
Kid,
Kid,
you!
kau!
Hi.
Hai.
Wait!
Tunggu!
Help me out!
Tolong aku!
Going down!
Kita terjatuh!
You're bleeding.
Kau berdarah.
Sonoko-san, excuse me.
Sonoko-san, maafkan aku.
What? What are you doing?
Apa? Apa yang kau lakukan?
What are you doing here?
Apa yang mau kau lakukan di sini?
Wait!
Tunggu!
It's a sling-rope carry.
Ini adalah gendongan tali selempang.
Sonoko-san, this time for sure,
Sonoko-san, kali ini pastikan,
Please don't go away.
tidak menjauh dariku.
I can't go away even if I wanted to.
Aku tidak bisa menjauh walau aku mau.
Where is he?
Di mana dia?
Kyogoku-san.
Kyogoku-san.
Grab something.
Berpegangan dengan sesuatu.
Are you alright?
Apa kau baik-baik saja?
I'll give it back.
Aku kembalikan.
That thing.
Benda itu.
It's not the jewel I'm looking for.
Itu bukan permata yang aku cari.
Sonoko-san.
Sonoko-san.
Could you sit over here for a minute?
Bisa kau duduk di sini sebentar?
I'm sorry.
Maafkan aku.
I tied a knot too tightly.
Aku mengikatnya terlalu kencang.
It's untied.
Sudah lepas.
No, that's...
Tidak, itu...
It's my good luck charm.
Itu adalah jimat keberuntunganku.
Have you been putting on this?
Apa kau selalu memakai ini?
Yes.
Iya.
I couldn't tell you because I thought it would reflect on my manly honor, but...
Aku tidak bisa memberitahumu karena rasa kehormatanku sebagai lelaki, tapi...
I see.
Begitu.
I thought I was always protected.
Aku mengira aku yang selalu dilindungi.
I was protecting you, Makoto-san.
Aku juga melindungimu, Makoto-san.
I see... I see...
Begitu... Begitu...
Please give me back the bandage.
Kumohon kembalikan perbannya.
No!
Tidak mau!
Please.
Kumohon.
- This is my treasure forever. - Sonoko-san.
- Ini adalah harta karunku selamanya. - Sonoko-san.
Lovey-dovey.
Mesra sekali.
Who the hell are you?
Siapa kau sebenarnya?
are you?
Apakah kau?
You're not just some kid.
Kau bukan anak-anak biasa.
Conan Edogawa.
Conan Edogawa.
I'm a detective.
Seorang detektif.
But is that okay?
Tapi apakah itu baik-baik saja?
You've let that strong boyfriend go to America, again.
Kau membiarkan pacar kuatmu pergi ke Amerika lagi.
It's okay.
Tidak apa-apa.
Makoto-san has to be fighting somewhere.
Makoto-san harus bertarung di tempat lain.
Oh, there they are.
Oh, di sana mereka.
What's that?
Apa itu?
Don't get so attached.
Jangan berpegangan terlalu kuat.
It's hard to walk.
Cukup sulit untuk berjalan.
I'll never let you go.
Aku tidak akan membiarkanmu pergi.
What? Really?
Apa? Benarkah?
I've been waiting a long time for this.
Aku sudah menantikan ini sejak lama.
This moment.
Momen ini.
I've been waiting for you, Kid.
Aku sudah menantikanmu, Kid.
Seriously.
Yang benar saja.
I knew you weren't Shinichi
Sudah kuduga kau bukan Shinichi...
from the beginning.
dari awal.
Shinichi
Shinichi.
What's that? -He never call
- Apa itu? - Dia tidak pernah memanggil...
my dad "Mister".
ayahku "Paman."
Because he's always calling him that.
Karena dia sering memanggilnya itu.
I've never called him "Mister" in front of Ran.
Aku tidak pernah memanggilnya "Paman" di depan Ran.
I can't believe it. You've disguised as Shinichi not once, but twice.
Aku tidak percaya. Kau menyamar sebagai Shinichi tidak hanya sekali, tapi dua kali.
I never forgive you.
Aku tidak akan memaafkanmu.
Don't you ever let go of his arm, young lady!
Jangan lepaskan tangannya, gadis muda!
Got it.
Dapat.
Kid.
Kid.
I won't let you go.
Aku tidak akan membiarkanmu pergi.
Don't let go.
Jangan lepaskan.
Hey, professor.
Hei, profesor.
He's not here.
Dia tidak ada di sini.
Oh, he's gone.
Oh, dia sudah melarikan diri.
Damn it.
Sialan.
He must still be close. Catch him.
Dia pasti masih dekat. Cari dia.
(EXIT)
(Pintu Keluar)
Conan-kun!
Conan-kun!
Welcome home, Ran-Neechan.
Selamat pulang kembali, Ran-Neechan.
I'm home.
Aku pulang.
Didn't you miss me?
Apa kau merindukanku?
No way.
Tidak mungkin.
I was with you all the time.
Aku selalu bersamamu di setiap waktu.
Reach out.
Mencapai.
(Great detective Conan) Faraway
(Conan Detektif Hebat) Menjauh.
(To be released in 2020GW!!)
(Akan di Rilis di 2020GW!!)